<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39531278</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4112</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The journal of ECT</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J ECT</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Evaluating Repetitive Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation for Neuropsychiatric Symptoms in Long COVID: A Case Series.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/YCT.0000000000001072</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To describe the immediate clinical outcomes of repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation (rTMS) in treating long COVID symptoms. Long COVID currently impacts approximately 5.3% of US adults, presenting with persistent fatigue, depression, anxiety, cognitive impairments, and social function decline. Repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation targeting the left dorsolateral prefrontal cortex has improved these symptoms in some studies.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Five patients (ages 52-63 years, 3 female patients) underwent accelerated rTMS using intermittent theta burst stimulation (600 pulses over 3 minutes 20 seconds, 80%-120% of resting motor threshold) to the left dorsolateral prefrontal cortex. The treatment consisted of twice-daily sessions over 20-30 treatments. Outcomes were measured using the Patient-Reported Outcomes Measurement and Information System (PROMIS) questionnaires, assessing fatigue, depression, anxiety, cognitive function, and social function at baseline and immediately posttreatment.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">One patient discontinued immediately due to intolerable scalp pain. Posttreatment PROMIS scores showed the following: fatigue decreased from 74.5 to 61.8, depression from 60.3 to 51.5, and anxiety from 62.0 to 54.0. Scores increased for cognitive (26.8 to 32.3) and social (31.0 to 32.5) function. These changes, although not statistically significant, indicate a trend toward symptom reduction. Subjectively, 3 of 4 patients who completed the rTMS course reported improvements.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This case series suggests that rTMS may offer symptomatic relief in long COVID patients. Although the observed improvements in PROMIS were not statistically significant, even minimal improvements are clinically significant for patients enduring prolonged suffering. These preliminary findings are encouraging and underscore the need for further research with larger cohorts to validate the efficacy of rTMS in long COVID symptom relief.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bock</LastName><ForeName>Jonathan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Mayo Clinic Alix School of Medicine.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kung</LastName><ForeName>Simon</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry and Psychology.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ganesh</LastName><ForeName>Ravindra</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of General Internal Medicine, Department of Internal Medicine, Mayo Clinic, Rochester, MN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hurt</LastName><ForeName>Ryan T</ForeName><Initials>RT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of General Internal Medicine, Department of Internal Medicine, Mayo Clinic, Rochester, MN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lapid</LastName><ForeName>Maria I</ForeName><Initials>MI</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry and Psychology.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J ECT</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9808943</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1095-0680</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>S.K. received an honorarium from Psychopharmacology Institute, for a video-recorded CME presentation regarding transcranial magnetic stimulation (TMS). M.I.L. currently receives NIA funding (AG061100) for an electroconvulsive therapy study unrelated to this article. She is principal investigator on an ongoing TMS study for mild cognitive impairment, holds an Investigational Device Exemption (G220016) from the US Food and Drug Administration as the sponsor-investigator, and receives study support from Nexstim, which provides TMS head trackers. M.I.L. declares no other conflict of interest. R.T.H. has received consulting fees from Nestle Nutrition, unrelated to this manuscript. The other authors have no conflicts of interest or financial disclosures to report.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>58</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>58</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39531278</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/YCT.0000000000001072</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124509-990000000-00218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Long COVID or post-COVID conditions [CDC Web site]. March 14, 2024. Available at: https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/long-term-effects/index.html. Accessed April 15, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long COVID: household pulse survey [CDC Web site]. April 18, 2024. Available at: https://www.cdc.gov/nchs/covid19/pulse/long-covid.htm. Accessed April 17, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Couzin-Frankel J. Clues to long COVID. Science. 2022;376:1261&#x2013;1265.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monje M, Iwasaki A. The neurobiology of long COVID. Neuron. 2022;110:3484&#x2013;3496.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noda Y, Sato A, Shichi M, et al. Real world research on transcranial magnetic stimulation treatment strategies for neuropsychiatric symptoms with long-COVID in Japan. Asian J Psychiatr. 2023;81:1034&#x2013;1038.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang JX, Zhang JJ. Case report of improvement in long-COVID symptoms in an air force medic treated with transcranial magnetic stimulation using electro-magnetic brain pulse technique. Mil Med. 2023;188:3711&#x2013;3715.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sasaki N, Yamatoku M, Tsuchida T, et al. Effect of repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation on long coronavirus disease 2019 with fatigue and cognitive dysfunction. Prog Rehabil Med. 2023;8:20230004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang CH, Chen SJ, Chen YC, et al. A 30-year-old woman with an 8-week history of anxiety, depression, insomnia, and mild cognitive impairment following COVID-19 who responded to accelerated bilateral theta-burst transcranial magnetic stimulation over the prefrontal cortex. Am J Case Rep. 2023;24:e938732.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>RECOVER-NEURO: platform protocol, appendix_A to measure the effects of BrainHQ, PASC CoRE and tDCS interventions on long COVID symptoms [NIH]. Trial number: NCT05965739. April 2, 2024. Available at: https://classic.clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT05965739. Accessed April 28, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>PROMIS score guide [Health Measures Web site]. March 27, 2023. Available at: https://www.healthmeasures.net/explore-measurement-systems/promis. Accessed April 10, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terwee CB, Peipert JD, Chapman R, et al. Minimal important change (MIC): a conceptual clarification and systematic review of MIC estimates of PROMIS measures. Qual Life Res. 2021;30:2729&#x2013;2754.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakib MN, Saragadam A, Santagata MC, et al. rTMS for post-COVID-19 condition: a sham-controlled case series involving iTBS-300 and iTBS-600. Brain Behav Immun Health. 2024;36:100736.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamamuta A, Takagi Y, Takahashi M, et al. Fatigue potentially reduces the effect of transcranial magnetic stimulation on depression following COVID-19 and its vaccination. Vaccines (Basel). 2023;11:1151.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feffer K, Fettes P, Giacobbe P, et al. 1 Hz rTMS of the right orbitofrontal cortex for major depression: safety, tolerability and clinical outcomes. Eur Neuropsychopharmacol. 2018;28:109&#x2013;117.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>