<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">39545965</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>20</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1433-8491</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>274</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European archives of psychiatry and clinical neuroscience</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur Arch Psychiatry Clin Neurosci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Is there a rationale for hyperbaric oxygen therapy in the patients with Post COVID syndrome? : A critical review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1797</StartPage><EndPage>1817</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1797-1817</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s00406-024-01911-y</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The SARS-CoV-2 pandemic has resulted in 762 million infections worldwide from 2020 to date, of which approximately ten percent are suffering from the effects after infection in 2019 (COVID-19) [1, 40]. In Germany, it is now assumed that at least one million people suffer from post-COVID condition with long-term consequences. These have been previously reported in diseases like Myalgic Encephalomyelitis (ME) and Chronic Fatigue Syndrome (CFS). Symptoms show a changing variability and recent surveys in the COVID context indicate that 10-30 % of outpatients, 50 to 70% of hospitalised patients suffer from sequelae. Recent data suggest that only 13% of all ill people were completely free of symptoms after recovery [3, 9]. Current hypotheses consider chronic inflammation, mitochondrial dysfunction, latent viral persistence, autoimmunity, changes of the human microbiome or multilocular sequelae in various organ system after infection. Hyperbaric oxygen therapy (HBOT) is applied since 1957 for heart surgery, scuba dive accidents, CO intoxication, air embolisms and infections with anaerobic pathogens. Under hyperbaric pressure, oxygen is physically dissolved in the blood in higher concentrations and reaches levels four times higher than under normobaric oxygen application. Moreover, the alternation of hyperoxia and normoxia induces a variety of processes at the cellular level, which improves oxygen supply in areas of locoregional hypoxia. Numerous target gene effects on new vessel formation, anti-inflammatory and anti-oedematous effects have been demonstrated [74]. The provision of intermittently high, local oxygen concentrations increases repair and regeneration processes and normalises the predominance of hyperinflammation. At present time only one prospective, randomized and placebo-controlled study exists with positive effects on global cognitive function, attention and executive function, psychiatric symptoms and pain interference. In conclusion, up to this date HBO is the only scientifically proven treatment in a prospective randomized controlled trial to be effective for cognitive improvement, regeneration of brain network and improvement of cardiac function. HBOT may have not only theoretical but also potential impact on targets of current pathophysiology of Post COVID condition, which warrants further scientific studies in patients.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pawlik</LastName><ForeName>M T</ForeName><Initials>MT</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4594-4841</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology and Intensive Care Medicine, Caritas-Hospital St. Joseph, University of Regensburg, Regensburg, Germany. mpawlik@csj.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Experimental Medicine, Christian-Albrechts-University of Kiel c/o German Naval Medical Institute, Kronshagen, Germany. mpawlik@csj.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rinneberg</LastName><ForeName>G</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology and Intensive Care Medicine, Caritas-Hospital St. Joseph, University of Regensburg, Regensburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Koch</LastName><ForeName>A</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Experimental Medicine, Christian-Albrechts-University of Kiel c/o German Naval Medical Institute, Kronshagen, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Meyringer</LastName><ForeName>H</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology and Intensive Care Medicine, Caritas-Hospital St. Joseph, University of Regensburg, Regensburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Loew</LastName><ForeName>T H</ForeName><Initials>TH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychosomatic Medicine, University Hospital Regensburg, Regensburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kjellberg</LastName><ForeName>A</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology and Pharmacology, Karolinska Institutet, Solna, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Perioperative Medicine and Intensive Care, Medical Unit Intensive Care and Thoracic surgery, Karolinska University Hospital, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Eur Arch Psychiatry Clin Neurosci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9103030</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0940-1334</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006931" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hyperbaric Oxygenation</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Brain fog</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chronic fatigue syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hyperbaric oxygen therapy (HBOT)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hypoxia-inducible-factor-1</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Post COVID condition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Conflict of interest: The authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any financial interest, which could be viewed as a potential conflict of interest. Ethical approval: Not applicable. Studies involving humans and/or animals: Not applicable. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Consent to participate: Not applicable.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39545965</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00406-024-01911-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s00406-024-01911-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11579208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Agarwal AK, Garg R, Ritch A, Sarkar P (2007) Postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome. Postgrad Med J 83:478&#x2013;480. 10.1136/pgmj.2006.055046</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2600095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17621618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Dalahmah O, Thakur KT, Nordvig AS, Prust ML, Roth W, Lignelli A, Uhlemann AC, Miller EH, Kunnath-Velayudhan S, Del Portillo A, Liu Y, Hargus G, Teich AF, Hickman RA, Tanji K, Goldman JE, Faust PL, Canoll P (2020) Neuronophagia and microglial nodules in a sars-cov-2 patient with cerebellar hemorrhage. Acta Neuropathol Commun 8:147. 10.1186/s40478-020-01024-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7447601</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32847628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ana N, Alvin Javid, Montgomery MK, Rajman L, James N, Eric D (2013) Declining nad + induces a pseudohypoxic state disrupting nuclear-mitochondrial communication during aging. Cell 155:1624&#x2013;1638. 10.1016/j.cell.2013.11.037</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4076149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24360282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arieli Y, Kotler D, Eynan M, Hochman A (2014) Hyperbaric oxygen preconditioning protects rats against cns oxygen toxicity. Respir Physiol Neurobiol 197:29&#x2013;35. 10.1016/j.resp.2014.03.006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24675062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnold DT, Hamilton FW, Milne A, Morley AJ, Viner J, Attwood M, Noel A, Gunning S, Hatrick J, Hamilton S, Elvers KT, Hyams C, Bibby A, Moran E, Adamali HI, Dodd JW, Maskell NA, Barratt SL (2021) Patient outcomes after hospitalisation with covid-19 and implications for follow-up: results from a prospective Uk cohort. Thorax 76:399&#x2013;401. 10.1136/thoraxjnl-2020-216086</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7716340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33273026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai X, Yao L, Ma X, Xu X (2018) Small molecules as sirt modulators. Mini Rev Med Chem 18:1151&#x2013;1157. 10.2174/1389557516666160620095103</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27334466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baig AM (2020) Computing the effects of sars-cov-2 on respiration regulatory mechanisms in covid-19. ACS Chem Neurosci 11:2416&#x2013;2421. 10.1021/acschemneuro.0c00349</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7422910</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32600045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baiula M, Greco R, Ferrazzano L, Caligiana A, Hoxha K, Bandini D, Longobardi P, Spampinato S, Tolomelli A (2020) Integrin-mediated adhesive properties of neutrophils are reduced by hyperbaric oxygen therapy in patients with chronic non-healing wound. PLoS ONE 15:e0237746. 10.1371/journal.pone.0237746</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7433869</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32810144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balasubramanian P, Delfavero J, Nyul-Toth A, Tarantini A, Gulej R, Tarantini S (2021) Integrative role of hyperbaric oxygen therapy on healthspan, age-related vascular cognitive impairment, and dementia. Front Aging 2:678543. 10.3389/fragi.2021.678543</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9261405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35821996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balestra C, Kot J (2021) Oxygen: a stimulus, not &#x201c;only&#x201d; a drug. Medicina. 10.3390/medicina57111161</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8623056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34833379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banks AS, Kon N, Knight C, Matsumoto M, Guti&#xe9;rrez-Ju&#xe1;rez R, Rossetti L, Gu W, Accili D (2008) Sirt1 gain of function increases energy efficiency and prevents diabetes in mice. Cell Metabol 8:333&#x2013;341. 10.1016/j.cmet.2008.08.014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3222897</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18840364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becker S, Schweinhardt P (2012) Dysfunctional neurotransmitter systems in fibromyalgia, their role in central stress circuitry and pharmacological actions on these systems. Pain Res Treat 2012:741746. 10.1155/2012/741746</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3195783</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22110944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bekheit M, Baddour N, Katri K, Taher Y, El Tobgy K, Mousa E (2016) Hyperbaric oxygen therapy stimulates colonic stem cells and induces mucosal healing in patients with refractory ulcerative colitis: a prospective case series. BMJ Open Gastroenterol 3:e000082. 10.1136/bmjgast-2016-000082</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4860723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27195128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benarroch EE (2018) Brainstem integration of arousal, sleep, cardiovascular, and respiratory control. Neurology 91:958&#x2013;966. 10.1212/WNL.0000000000006537</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30355703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benghanem S, Mazeraud A, Azabou E, Chhor V, Shinotsuka CR, Claassen J, Rohaut B, Sharshar T (2020) Brainstem dysfunction in critically ill patients. Crit Care 24:5. 10.1186/s13054-019-2718-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6945639</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31907011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benincasa JC, de Freitas Filho LH, Carneiro GD, Sielski MS, Giorgio S, Werneck CC, Vicente CP (2019) Hyperbaric oxygen affects endothelial progenitor cells proliferation in vitro. Cell Biol Int 43:136&#x2013;146. 10.1002/cbin.11070</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30362212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boerema IM, Brummelkamp NG, Bouma HW, Mensch S, van Anderen MH, W (1960) Life without blood. Ned Tijdschr Geneeskd 104:949&#x2013;954</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13802034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borab Z, Mirmanesh MD, Gantz M, Cusano A, Pu LL (2017) Systematic review of hyperbaric oxygen therapy for the treatment of radiation-induced skin necrosis. J Plast Reconstr Aesthet Surg 70:529&#x2013;538. 10.1016/j.bjps.2016.11.024</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28081957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouck EG, Denorme F, Holle LA, Middelton EA, Blair AM, de Laat B, Schiffman JD, Yost CC, Rondina MT, Wolberg AS, Campbell RA (2021) Covid-19 and sepsis are associated with different abnormalities in plasma procoagulant and fibrinolytic activity. Arterioscler Thromb Vasc Biol 41:401&#x2013;414. 10.1161/ATVBAHA.120.315338</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7942774</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33196292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brismar K, Lind F, Kratz G (1997) Dose-dependent hyperbaric oxygen stimulation of human fibroblast proliferation. Wound Repair Regen 5:147&#x2013;150. 10.1046/j.1524-475X.1997.50206.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16984424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brugniaux JV, Coombs GB, Barak OF, Dujic Z, Sekhon MS, Ainslie PN (2018) Highs and lows of hyperoxia: physiological, performance, and clinical aspects. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol 315:R1&#x2013;R27. 10.1152/ajpregu.00165.2017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29488785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carfi A, Bernabei R, Landi F, Gemelli Against COVID-19 Post-Acute Care Study Group (2020) Persistent symptoms in patients after acute covid-19. JAMA 324:603&#x2013;605. 10.1001/jama.2020.12603</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7349096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32644129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carreau A, Hafny-Rahbi BE, Matejuk A, Grillon C, Kieda C (2011) Why is the partial oxygen pressure of human tissues a crucial parameter? Small molecules and hypoxia. J Cell Mol Med 15:1239&#x2013;1253. 10.1111/j.1582-4934.2011.01258.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4373326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21251211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cascella M, Rajnik M, Aleem A, Dulebohn SC, Di Napoli R (2022) Features, evaluation, and treatment of coronavirus (covid-19). Statpearls, Treasure Island</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32150360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Case LC, Tessier-Lavigne M (2005) Regeneration of the adult central nervous system. Curr Biol 15:R749&#x2013;R753. 10.1016/j.cub.2005.09.008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16169471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Catalogna M, Sasson E, Hadanny A, Parag Y, Zilberman-Itskovich S, Efrati S (2022) Effects of hyperbaric oxygen therapy on functional and structural connectivity in post-covid-19 condition patients: a randomized, sham-controlled trial. NeuroImage: Clin. 10.1016/j.nicl.2022.103218</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9528018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36208548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Catalogna MHA, Parag Y, Adler M, Elkarif V, Efrati S (2023) Functional mri evaluation of hyperbaric oxygen therapy effect on hand motor recovery in a chronic post-stroke patient: a case report and physiological discussion. Front Neurol. 10.3389/fneur.2023.1233841</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10570419</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37840920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen J, Berry MJ (2004) Selenium and selenoproteins in the brain and brain diseases. J Neurochem 86:1&#x2013;12. 10.1046/j.1471-4159.2003.01854.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12807419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen R, Dioum EM, Hogg RT, Gerard RD, Garcia JA (2011) Hypoxia increases sirtuin 1 expression in a hypoxia-inducible factor-dependent manner. J Biol Chem 286:13869&#x2013;13878. 10.1074/jbc.m110.175414</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3077588</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21345792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen X, You J, Ma H, Zhou M, Huang C (2023) Efficacy and safety of hyperbaric oxygen therapy for fibromyalgia: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMJ Open 13:e062322. 10.1136/bmjopen-2022-062322</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9872467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36690401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chigr F, Merzouki M, Najimi M (2020) Autonomic brain centers and pathophysiology of covid-19. ACS Chem Neurosci 11:1520&#x2013;1522. 10.1021/acschemneuro.0c00265</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32427468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chu HX, Jones NM (2016) Changes in hypoxia-inducible factor-1 (hif-1) and regulatory prolyl hydroxylase (phd) enzymes following hypoxic-ischemic injury in the neonatal rat. Neurochem Res 41:515&#x2013;522. 10.1007/s11064-015-1641-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26108712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cimino F, Balestra C, Germonpre P, De Bels D, Tillmans F, Saija A, Speciale A, Virgili F (2012) Pulsed high oxygen induces a hypoxic-like response in human umbilical endothelial cells and in humans. J Appl Physiol 113:1684&#x2013;1689. 10.1152/japplphysiol.00922.2012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23042909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dann CE, Bruick RK, Deisenhofer J (2002) Structure of factor-inhibiting hypoxia-inducible factor 1: an asparaginyl hydroxylase involved in the hypoxic response pathway. Proc Natl Acad Sci 99:15351&#x2013;15356. 10.1073/pnas.202614999</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC137720</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12432100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Datta SD, Talwar A, Lee JT (2020) A proposed framework and timeline of the spectrum of disease due to sars-cov-2 infection: illness beyond acute infection and public health implications. JAMA 324:2251&#x2013;2252. 10.1001/jama.2020.22717</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33206133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, McCorkell L, Vogel JM, Topol EJ (2023) Long covid: major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nat Rev Microbiol 21:133&#x2013;146. 10.1038/s41579-022-00846-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9839201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36639608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Wolde SD, Hulskes RH, de Jonge SW, Hollmann MW, van Hulst RA, Weenink RP, Kox M (2022) The effect of hyperbaric oxygen therapy on markers of oxidative stress and the immune response in healthy volunteers. Front Physiol 13:826163. 10.3389/fphys.2022.826163</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8843016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35173631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deigendesch N, Sironi L, Kutza M, Wischnewski S, Fuchs V, Hench J, Frank A, Nienhold R, Mertz KD, Cathomas G, Matter MS, Siegemund M, Tolnay M, Schirmer L, Probstel AK, Tzankov A, Frank S (2020) Correlates of critical illness-related encephalopathy predominate postmortem covid-19 neuropathology. Acta Neuropathol 140:583&#x2013;586. 10.1007/s00401-020-02213-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7449525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32851506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Denaro CA, Haloush YI, Hsiao SY, Orgera JJ, Osorio T, Riggs LM, Sassaman JW, Williams SA, Monte Carlo III, Anthony R, Da Costa RT, Grigoriev A, Solesio ME (2022) Covid-19 and neurodegeneration: the mitochondrial connection. Aging Cell 21:e13727. 10.1111/acel.13727</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9649608</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36219531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dennog C, Radermacher P, Barnett YA, Speit G (1999) Antioxidant status in humans after exposure to hyperbaric oxygen. Mutat Res 428:83&#x2013;89. 10.1016/s1383-5742(99)00034-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10517981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dey J, Alam MT, Chandra S, Gupta J, Ray U, Srivastava AK, Tripathi PP (2021) Neuroinvasion of sars-cov&#x2010;2 may play a role in the breakdown of the respiratory center of the brain. J Med Virol 93:1296&#x2013;1303. 10.1002/jmv.26521</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32964419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diamond MS, Kanneganti TD (2022) Innate immunity: the first line of defense against sars-cov-2. Nat Immunol 23:165&#x2013;176. 10.1038/s41590-021-01091-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8935980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35105981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Efrati S, Ben-Jacob E (2014) Reflections on the neurotherapeutic effects of hyperbaric oxygen. Expert Rev Neurother 14:233&#x2013;236. 10.1586/14737175.2014.884928</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24471697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fabbri VP, Foschini MP, Lazzarotto T, Gabrielli L, Cenacchi G, Gallo C, Aspide R, Frascaroli G, Cortelli P, Riefolo M, Giannini C, D&#x2019;Errico A (2021) Brain ischemic injury in covid-19-infected patients: a series of 10 post-mortem cases. Brain Pathol 31:205&#x2013;210. 10.1111/bpa.12901</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7536900</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33002281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feigin VL, Stark BA, Johnson CO, Roth GA, Bisignano C, Abady GG, Abbasifard M, Abbasi-Kangevari M, Abd-Allah F, Abedi V, Abualhasan A, Abu-Rmeileh NM, Abushouk AI, Adebayo OM, Agarwal G, Agasthi P, Ahinkorah BO, Ahmad S, Ahmadi S, Ahmed Salih Y, Aji B, Akbarpour S, Akinyemi RO, Al Hamad H, Alahdab F, Alif SM, Alipour V, Aljunid SM, Almustanyir S, Al-Raddadi RM, Al-Shahi Salman R, Alvis-Guzman N, Ancuceanu R, Anderlini D, Anderson JA, Ansar A, Antonazzo IC, Arabloo J, &#xc4;rnl&#xf6;v J, Artanti KD, Aryan Z, Asgari S, Ashraf T, Athar M, Atreya A, Ausloos M, Baig AA, Baltatu OC, Banach M, Barboza MA, Barker-Collo SL, B&#xe4;rnighausen TW, Barone MTU, Basu S, Bazmandegan G, Beghi E, Beheshti M, B&#xe9;jot Y, Bell AW, Bennett DA, Bensenor IM, Bezabhe WM, Bezabih YM, Bhagavathula AS, Bhardwaj P, Bhattacharyya K, Bijani A, Bikbov B, Birhanu MM, Boloor A, Bonny A, Brauer M, Brenner H, Bryazka D, Butt ZA, Caetano Dos Santos FL, Campos-Nonato IR, Cantu-Brito C, Carrero JJ, Casta&#xf1;eda-Orjuela CA, Catapano AL, Chakraborty PA, Charan J, Choudhari SG, Chowdhury EK, Chu D-T, Chung S-C, Colozza D, Costa VM, Costanzo S, Criqui MH, Dadras O, Dagnew B, Dai X, Dalal K, Damasceno AAM, D&#x2019;Amico E, Dandona L, Dandona R, Darega Gela J et al (2021) Global, regional, and national burden of stroke and its risk factors, 1990&#x2013;2019: a systematic analysis for the global burden of disease study 2019. The Lancet Neurology 20:795&#x2013;820. 10.1016/s1474-4422(21)00252-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8443449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34487721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feldmeier JJ, Kirby JP, Buckey JC, Denham DW, Evangelista JS, Gelly HB, Harlan NP, Mirza ZK, Ray KL, Robins M, Savaser DJ, Wainwright S, Bird N, Huang ET, Moon RE, Thom SR, Weaver LK (2021) Physiologic and biochemical rationale for treating covid-19 patients with hyperbaric oxygen. Undersea Hyperb Med 48:1&#x2013;12. 10.22462/01.03.2021.1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33648028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Firestein R, Blander G, Michan S, Oberdoerffer P, Ogino S, Campbell J, Bhimavarapu A, Luikenhuis S, De Cabo R, Fuchs C, Hahn WC, Guarente LP, Sinclair DA (2008) The sirt1 deacetylase suppresses intestinal tumorigenesis and colon cancer growth. PLoS ONE 3:e2020. 10.1371/journal.pone.0002020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2289879</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18414679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fischer I, Barak B (2020) Molecular and therapeutic aspects of hyperbaric oxygen therapy in neurological conditions. Biomolecules 10:1247. 10.3390/biom10091247</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7564723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32867291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fosen KM, Thom SR (2014) Hyperbaric oxygen, vasculogenic stem cells, and wound healing. Antioxid Redox Signal 21:1634&#x2013;1647. 10.1089/ars.2014.5940</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4175035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24730726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gandhi S, Srivastava AK, Ray U, Tripathi PP (2020) Is the collapse of the respiratory center in the brain responsible for respiratory breakdown in covid-19 patients? ACS Chem Neurosci 11:1379&#x2013;1381. 10.1021/acschemneuro.0c00217</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32348111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao L, Chen Q, Zhou X, Fan L (2012) The role of hypoxia-inducible factor 1 in atherosclerosis. J Clin Pathol 65:872&#x2013;876. 10.1136/jclinpath-2012-200828</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22569539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia Estevez DA, Lopez Perez A, Gomez Marquez H (2023) Hyperbaric oxygen therapy in long-covid-19 disease. Med Clin. 10.1016/j.medcli.2023.06.046</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37775412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gill AL, Bell CN (2004) Hyperbaric oxygen: its uses, mechanisms of action and outcomes. QJM 97:385&#x2013;395. 10.1093/qjmed/hch074</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15208426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzales-Portillo B, Lippert T, Nguyen H, Lee JY, Borlongan CV (2019) Hyperbaric oxygen therapy: a new look on treating stroke and traumatic brain injury. Brain Circ 5:101&#x2013;105. 10.4103/bc.bc_31_19</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6785945</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31620655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gottfried I, Schottlender N, Ashery U (2021) Hyperbaric oxygen treatment-from mechanisms to cognitive improvement. Biomolecules. 10.3390/biom11101520</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8533945</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34680155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenhalgh T, Knight M, A&#x2019;Court C, Buxton M, Husain L (2020) Management of post-acute covid-19 in primary care. BMJ 370:m3026. 10.1136/bmj.m3026</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32784198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grifoni E, Vannucchi V, Valoriani A, Cei F, Lamanna R, Gelli AMG, Ciambotti B, Moroni F, Pelagatti L, Tarquini R, Landini G, Vanni S, Masotti L (2021) Interleukin-6 added to call score better predicts the prognosis of covid-19 patients. Intern Med J 51:146&#x2013;147. 10.1111/imj.14974</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33336833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Groger M, Radermacher P, Speit G, Muth CM (2008) Genotoxicity of hyperbaric oxygen and its prevention: what hyperbaric physicians should know. Diving Hyperb Med 38:200&#x2013;205. https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/22692753
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22692753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Groger M, Oter S, Simkova V, Bolten M, Koch A, Warninghoff V, Georgieff M, Muth CM, Speit G, Radermacher P (2009) DNA damage after long-term repetitive hyperbaric oxygen exposure. J Appl Physiol 106:311&#x2013;315. 10.1152/japplphysiol.90737.2008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19023023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grover M, Herfarth H, Drossman DA (2009) The functional-organic dichotomy: Postinfectious irritable bowel syndrome and inflammatory bowel disease-irritable bowel syndrome. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol 7:48&#x2013;53. 10.1016/j.cgh.2008.08.032</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18848909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xfc;nter Speit CD, Lorenz Lampl (1998) Biological significance of DNA damage induced by hbo. Mutagenesis 13:85&#x2013;87</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9491400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haber SN (2003) The primate basal ganglia: parallel and integrative networks. J Chem Neuroanat 26:317&#x2013;330. 10.1016/j.jchemneu.2003.10.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14729134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hadanny A, Efrati S (2020) The hyperoxic-hypoxic paradox. Biomolecules. 10.3390/biom10060958</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7355982</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32630465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hadanny A, Bechor Y, Catalogna M, Daphna-Tekoah S, Sigal T, Cohenpour M, Lev-Wiesel R, Efrati S (2018) Hyperbaric oxygen therapy can induce neuroplasticity and significant clinical improvement in patients suffering from fibromyalgia with a history of childhood sexual abuse-randomized controlled trial. Front Psychol 9:2495. 10.3389/fpsyg.2018.02495</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6304433</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30618929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hadanny A, Zilberman-Itskovich S, Catalogna M, Elman-Shina K, Lang E, Finci S, Polak N, Shorer R, Parag Y, Efrati S (2024) Long term outcomes of hyperbaric oxygen therapy in post covid condition: longitudinal follow-up of a randomized controlled trial. Sci Rep 14:3604. 10.1038/s41598-024-53091-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10869702</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38360929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hafer-Macko C, Hsieh ST, Li CY, Ho TW, Sheikh K, Cornblath DR, McKhann GM, Asbury AK, Griffin JW (1996) Acute motor axonal neuropathy: an antibody-mediated attack on axolemma. Ann Neurol 40:635&#x2013;644. 10.1002/ana.410400414</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8871584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haffke M, Freitag H, Rudolf G, Seifert M, Doehner W, Scherbakov N, Hanitsch L, Wittke K, Bauer S, Konietschke F, Paul F, Bellmann-Strobl J, Kedor C, Scheibenbogen C, Sotzny F (2022) Endothelial dysfunction and altered endothelial biomarkers in patients with post-covid-19 syndrome and chronic fatigue syndrome (me/cfs). J Transl Med 20:138. 10.1186/s12967-022-03346-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8938726</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35317812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han N, Pan Z, Liu G, Yang R, Yujing B (2021) Hypoxia: the invisible pusher of gut microbiota. Front Microbiol 12:690600. 10.3389/fmicb.2021.690600</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8339470</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34367091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hedetoft M, Madsen MB, Madsen LB, Hyldegaard O (2020) Incidence, comorbidity and mortality in patients with necrotising soft-tissue infections, 2005&#x2013;2018: a Danish nationwide register-based cohort study. BMJ Open 10:e041302. 10.1136/bmjopen-2020-041302</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7569942</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33067303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirata T, Cui YJ, Funakoshi T, Mizukami Y, Ishikawa Y, Shibasaki F, Matsumoto M, Sakabe T (2007) The temporal profile of genomic responses and protein synthesis in ischemic tolerance of the rat brain induced by repeated hyperbaric oxygen. Brain Res 1130:214&#x2013;222. 10.1016/j.brainres.2006.10.077</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17173873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho M, Jaffe R, Miller G, Breinig MK, Dummer JS, Makowka L, Atchison RW, Karrer F, Nalesnik MA, Starzl TE (1988) The frequency of epstein-barr virus infection and associated lymphoproliferative syndrome after transplantation and its manifestations in children. Transplantation 45:719&#x2013;726. 10.1097/00007890-198804000-00011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2993427</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2833828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hollander DA, Hakimi MY, Hartmann A, Wilhelm K, Windolf J (2000) The influence of hyperbaric oxygenation (hbo) on proliferation and differentiation of human keratinocyte cultures in vitro. Cell Tissue Bank 1:261&#x2013;269. 10.1023/A:1010145312698</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15256935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu B, Guo H, Zhou P, Shi ZL (2021) Characteristics of sars-cov-2 and covid-19. Nat Rev Microbiol 19:141&#x2013;154. 10.1038/s41579-020-00459-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7537588</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33024307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huebner EA, Strittmatter SM (2009) Axon regeneration in the peripheral and central nervous systems. Results Probl Cell Differ 48:339&#x2013;351. 10.1007/400_2009_19</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2846285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19582408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ighodaro OM, Akinloye OA (2019) First line defence antioxidants-superoxide dismutase (sod), catalase (cat) and glutathione peroxidase (gpx): their fundamental role in the entire antioxidant defence grid. Alexandria J Med 54:287&#x2013;293. 10.1016/j.ajme.2017.09.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Itoi K, Sugimoto N (2010) The brainstem noradrenergic systems in stress, anxiety and depression. J Neuroendocrinol 22:355&#x2013;361. 10.1111/j.1365-2826.2010.01988.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20210846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iwasaki M, Saito J, Zhao H, Sakamoto A, Hirota K, Ma D (2021) Inflammation triggered by sars-cov-2 and ace2 augment drives multiple organ failure of severe covid-19: molecular mechanisms and implications. Inflammation 44:13&#x2013;34. 10.1007/s10753-020-01337-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7541099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33029758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaskiewicz M, Moszynska A, Serocki M, Kroliczewski J, Bartoszewska S, Collawn JF, Bartoszewski R (2022) Hypoxia-inducible factor (hif)-3a2 serves as an endothelial cell fate executor during chronic hypoxia. EXCLI J 21:454&#x2013;469. 10.17179/excli2021-4622</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8983852</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35391921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kemmer A (2001) Akute und notfallindikationen f&#xfc;r die hyperbare oxygenierungstherapie (hbo). Trauma Berufskrankh 3:262&#x2013;266</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan S, Gomes J (2020) Neuropathogenesis of sars-cov-2 infection. eLife. 10.7554/elife.59136</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7392602</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32729463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kitala D, &#x141;abu&#x15b; W, Kozielski J, Strzelec P, Nowak M, Knefel G, Dyjas P, Materniak K, Kosmala J, Paj&#x105;k J, Czop J, Janda-Kalus B, Marona B, Nowak-Wr&#xf3;&#x17c;yna A, Gierek M, Szczegielniak J, Kucharzewski M (2022) Preliminary research on the effect of hyperbaric oxygen therapy in patients with post-covid-19 syndrome. J Clin Med. 10.3390/jcm12010308</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9821575</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36615108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kivisaari J, Vihersaari T, Renvall S, Niinikoski J (1975) Energy metabolism of experimental wounds at various oxygen environments. Ann Surg 181:823&#x2013;828. 10.1097/00000658-197506000-00011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1343902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1138632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kjellberg A, De Maio A, Lindholm P (2020) Can hyperbaric oxygen safely serve as an anti-inflammatory treatment for covid-19? Med Hypotheses. 10.1016/j.mehy.2020.110224</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7456590</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33254531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kjellberg A, Douglas J, Pawlik MT, Kraus M, Oscarsson N, Zheng X, Bergman P, Franberg O, Kowalski JH, Nyren SP, Silvanius M, Skold M, Catrina SB, Rodriguez-Wallberg KA, Lindholm P (2021) Randomised, controlled, open label, multicentre clinical trial to explore safety and efficacy of hyperbaric oxygen for preventing icu admission, morbidity and mortality in adult patients with covid-19. BMJ Open 11:e046738. 10.1136/bmjopen-2020-046738</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8260306</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34226219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kjellberg A, Abdel-Halim L, Hassler A, El Gharbi S, Al-Ezerjawi S, Bostrom E, Sundberg CJ, Pernow J, Medson K, Kowalski JH, Rodriguez-Wallberg KA, Zheng X, Catrina S, Runold M, Stahlberg M, Bruchfeld J, Nygren-Bonnier M, Lindholm P (2022) Hyperbaric oxygen for treatment of long covid-19 syndrome (hot-loco): protocol for a randomised, placebo-controlled, double-blind, phase ii clinical trial. BMJ Open 12:e061870. 10.1136/bmjopen-2022-061870</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9638753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36323462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kjellberg A, Hassler A, Bostrom E, El Gharbi S, Al-Ezerjawi S, Kowalski J, Rodriguez-Wallberg KA, Bruchfeld J, Stahlberg M, Nygren-Bonnier M, Runold M, Lindholm P (2023) Hyperbaric oxygen therapy for long covid (hot-loco), an interim safety report from a randomised controlled trial. BMC Infect Dis 23:33. 10.1186/s12879-023-08002-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9854077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36670365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koch A, Kahler W, Klapa S, Grams B, van Ooij PAM (2020) The conundrum of using hyperoxia in covid-19 treatment strategies: May intermittent therapeutic hyperoxia play a helpful role in the expression of the surface receptors ace2 and furin in lung tissue via triggering of hif-1alpha? Intensive Care Med Exp 8:53. 10.1186/s40635-020-00323-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7490775</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32953400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kupferschmitt A, Langheim E, Tuter H, Etzrodt F, Loew TH, Kollner V (2022) First results from post-covid inpatient rehabilitation. Front Rehabil Sci 3:1093871. 10.3389/fresc.2022.1093871</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9899863</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36756465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee Y-S, Chio C-C, Chang C-P, Wang L-C, Chiang P-M, Niu K-C, Tsai K-J (2013) Long course hyperbaric oxygen stimulates neurogenesis and attenuates inflammation after ischemic stroke. Mediat Inflamm 2013:1&#x2013;13. 10.1155/2013/512978</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3595722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23533308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leitman M, Fuchs S, Tyomkin V, Hadanny A, Zilberman-Itskovich S, Efrati S (2023) The effect of hyperbaric oxygen therapy on myocardial function in post-covid-19 syndrome patients: a randomized controlled trial. Sci Rep. 10.1038/s41598-023-36570-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10257166</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37301934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li K, Wohlford-Lenane C, Perlman S, Zhao J, Jewell AK, Reznikov LR, Gibson-Corley KN, Meyerholz DK, McCray PB Jr (2016) Middle east respiratory syndrome coronavirus causes multiple organ damage and lethal disease in mice transgenic for human dipeptidyl peptidase 4. J Infect Dis 213:712&#x2013;722. 10.1093/infdis/jiv499</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4747621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26486634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Hao Y-F, Wang T, Zhang J-F, Liang Y, Xiao W-L, Guo X (2019) Hyperbaric oxygen may improve vascular endothelial function in patients undergoing coronary stent implantation. Undersea Hyperb Med 46:145&#x2013;152</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31051059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li YC, Bai WZ, Hashikawa T (2020) The neuroinvasive potential of sars-cov2 may play a role in the respiratory failure of covid-19 patients. J Med Virol 92:552&#x2013;555. 10.1002/jmv.25728</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7228394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32104915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao M, Liu Y, Yuan J, Wen Y, Xu G, Zhao J, Cheng L, Li J, Wang X, Wang F, Liu L, Amit I, Zhang S, Zhang Z (2020) Single-cell landscape of bronchoalveolar immune cells in patients with covid-19. Nat Med 26:842&#x2013;844. 10.1038/s41591-020-0901-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32398875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim J-H, Lee Y-M, Chun Y-S, Chen J, Kim J-E, Park J-W (2010) Sirtuin 1 modulates cellular responses to hypoxia by deacetylating hypoxia-inducible factor 1&#x3b1;. Mol Cell 38:864&#x2013;878. 10.1016/j.molcel.2010.05.023</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20620956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin SS, Ueng SW, Niu CC, Yuan LJ, Yang CY, Chen WJ, Lee MS, Chen JK (2014) Effects of hyperbaric oxygen on the osteogenic differentiation of mesenchymal stem cells. BMC Musculoskelet Disord 15:56. 10.1186/1471-2474-15-56</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3938030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24568330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindenmann J, Porubsky C, Okresa L, Klemen H, Mykoliuk I, Roj A, Koutp A, Kink E, Iberer F, Kovacs G, Krause R, Smolle J, Smolle-Juettner FM (2023) Immediate and long-term effects of hyperbaric oxygenation in patients with long covid-19 syndrome using sf-36 survey and vas score: a clinical pilot study. J Clin Med 12:6253. 10.3390/jcm12196253</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10573231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37834897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Q, Mak JWY, Su Q, Yeoh YK, Lui GC, Ng SSS, Zhang F, Li AYL, Lu W, Hui DS, Chan PK, Chan FKL, Ng SC (2022) Gut microbiota dynamics in a prospective cohort of patients with post-acute covid-19 syndrome. Gut 71:544&#x2013;552. 10.1136/gutjnl-2021-325989</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35082169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loughlin SE, Fallon JH (1984) Substantia Nigra and ventral tegmental area projections to cortex: Topography and collateralization. Neuroscience 11:425&#x2013;435. 10.1016/0306-4522(84)90034-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6201780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu Y, Li X, Geng D, Mei N, Wu PY, Huang CC, Jia T, Zhao Y, Wang D, Xiao A, Yin B (2020) Cerebral micro-structural changes in covid-19 patients - an mri-based 3-month follow-up study. EClinicalMedicine 25:100484. 10.1016/j.eclinm.2020.100484</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7396952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32838240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ludvigsson JF (2021) Case report and systematic review suggest that children may experience similar long-term effects to adults after clinical covid-19. Acta Paediatr 110:914&#x2013;921. 10.1111/apa.15673</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7753397</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33205450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Makhluf H, Madany H, Kim K (2024) Long covid: long-term impact of sars-cov2. Diagnostics 14:711</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11011397</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38611624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandal S, Barnett J, Brill SE, Brown JS, Denneny EK, Hare SS, Heightman M, Hillman TE, Jacob J, Jarvis HC, Lipman MCI, Naidu SB, Nair A, Porter JC, Tomlinson GS, Hurst JR, Group ARCS (2021) Long-covid&#x2019;: a cross-sectional study of persisting symptoms, biomarker and imaging abnormalities following hospitalisation for covid-19. Thorax 76:396&#x2013;398. 10.1136/thoraxjnl-2020-215818</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7615158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33172844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marchetti M (2020) Covid-19-driven endothelial damage: complement, hif-1, and abl2 are potential pathways of damage and targets for cure. Ann Hematol 99:1701&#x2013;1707. 10.1007/s00277-020-04138-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7312112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32583086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matschke J, Lutgehetmann M, Hagel C, Sperhake JP, Schroder AS, Edler C, Mushumba H, Fitzek A, Allweiss L, Dandri M, Dottermusch M, Heinemann A, Pfefferle S, Schwabenland M, Sumner Magruder D, Bonn S, Prinz M, Gerloff C, Puschel K, Krasemann S, Aepfelbacher M, Glatzel M (2020) Neuropathology of patients with covid-19 in Germany: a post-mortem case series. Lancet Neurol 19:919&#x2013;929. 10.1016/S1474-4422(20)30308-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7535629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33031735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsushima S, Sadoshima J (2015) The role of sirtuins in cardiac disease. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol 309:H1375&#x2013;1389. 10.1152/ajpheart.00053.2015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4666968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26232232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCray PB Jr., Pewe L, Wohlford-Lenane C, Hickey M, Manzel L, Shi L, Netland J, Jia HP, Halabi C, Sigmund CD, Meyerholz DK, Kirby P, Look DC, Perlman S (2007) Lethal infection of k18-hace2 mice infected with severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus. J Virol 81:813&#x2013;821. 10.1128/JVI.02012-06</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1797474</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17079315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Medini H, Zirman A, Mishmar D (2021) Immune system cells from covid-19 patients display compromised mitochondrial-nuclear expression co-regulation and rewiring toward glycolysis. iScience. 10.1016/j.isci.2021.103471</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8599136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34812416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehandru S, Merad M (2022) Pathological sequelae of long-haul covid. Nat Immunol 23:194&#x2013;202. 10.1038/s41590-021-01104-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9127978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35105985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meinhardt J, Radke J, Dittmayer C, Franz J, Thomas C, Mothes R, Laue M, Schneider J, Brunink S, Greuel S, Lehmann M, Hassan O, Aschman T, Schumann E, Chua RL, Conrad C, Eils R, Stenzel W, Windgassen M, Rossler L, Goebel HH, Gelderblom HR, Martin H, Nitsche A, Schulz-Schaeffer WJ, Hakroush S, Winkler MS, Tampe B, Scheibe F, Kortvelyessy P, Reinhold D, Siegmund B, Kuhl AA, Elezkurtaj S, Horst D, Oesterhelweg L, Tsokos M, Ingold-Heppner B, Stadelmann C, Drosten C, Corman VM, Radbruch H, Heppner FL (2021) Olfactory transmucosal sars-cov-2 invasion as a port of central nervous system entry in individuals with covid-19. Nat Neurosci 24:168&#x2013;175. 10.1038/s41593-020-00758-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33257876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyazato Y, Morioka S, Tsuzuki S, Akashi M, Osanai Y, Tanaka K, Terada M, Suzuki M, Kutsuna S, Saito S, Hayakawa K, Ohmagari N (2020) Prolonged and late-onset symptoms of coronavirus disease 2019. Open Forum Infect Dis 7:ofaa507. 10.1093/ofid/ofaa507</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7665672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33230486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MJTPSDMSLMB-LRDFSVVALW-K SHEN, LOW APA (2007) Postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrom the mayo clinic experience. Mayo Clin Proc 82:308&#x2013;313</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17352367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohiuddin M, Kasahara K (2022) Cancer metastasis may increase covid-19 mortality: suitable targets required to impede cancer metastasis. J Infect Public Health 15:153&#x2013;155. 10.1016/j.jiph.2021.12.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8662903</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34929552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohyeldin A, Garz&#xf3;n-Muvdi T, Qui&#xf1;ones-Hinojosa A (2010) Oxygen in stem cell biology: a critical component of the stem cell niche. Cell Stem Cell 7:150&#x2013;161. 10.1016/j.stem.2010.07.007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20682444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mrakic-Sposta S, Vezzoli A, Garetto G, Paganini M, Camporesi E, Giacon TA, Dellanoce C, Agrimi J, Bosco G (2023) Hyperbaric oxygen therapy counters oxidative stress/inflammation-driven symptoms in long covid-19 patients: preliminary outcomes. Metabolites. 10.3390/metabo13101032</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10608857</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37887357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nath A (2020) Long-haul covid. Neurology 95:559&#x2013;560. 10.1212/wnl.0000000000010640</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32788251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Netland J, Meyerholz DK, Moore S, Cassell M, Perlman S (2008) Severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus infection causes neuronal death in the absence of encephalitis in mice transgenic for human ace2. J Virol 82:7264&#x2013;7275. 10.1128/JVI.00737-08</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2493326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18495771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niu CC, Yuan LJ, Chen LH, Lin SS, Tsai TT, Liao JC, Lai PL, Chen WJ (2011) Beneficial effects of hyperbaric oxygen on human degenerated intervertebral disk cells via suppression of il-1beta and p38 mapk signal. J Orthop Res 29:14&#x2013;19. 10.1002/jor.21195</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20661932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niu C-C, Lin S-S, Yuan L-J, Lu M-L, Ueng SWN, Yang C-Y, Tsai T-T, Lai P-L (2019) Upregulation of mir-107 expression following hyperbaric oxygen treatment suppresses hmgb1/rage signaling in degenerated human nucleus pulposus cells. Arthritis Res Therapy. 10.1186/s13075-019-1830-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6357369</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30704538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Notarte KI, Catahay JA, Velasco JV, Pastrana A, Ver AT, Pangilinan FC, Peligro PJ, Casimiro M, Guerrero JJ, Gellaco MML, Lippi G, Henry BM, Fern&#xe1;ndez-De-Las-Pe&#xf1;as C (2022) Impact of covid-19 vaccination on the risk of developing long-covid and on existing long-covid symptoms: a systematic review. eClinicalMedicine 53:101624. 10.1016/j.eclinm.2022.101624</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9417563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36051247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osmanov IM, Spiridonova E, Bobkova P, Gamirova A, Shikhaleva A, Andreeva M, Blyuss O, El-Taravi Y, Dunngalvin A, Comberiati P, Peroni DG, Apfelbacher C, Genuneit J, Mazankova L, Miroshina A, Chistyakova E, Samitova E, Borzakova S, Bondarenko E, Korsunskiy AA, Konova I, Hanson SW, Carson G, Sigfrid L, Scott JT, Greenhawt M, Whittaker EA, Garralda E, Swann OV, Buonsenso D, Nicholls DE, Simpson F, Jones C, Semple MG, Warner JO, Vos T, Olliaro P, Munblit D (2022) Risk factors for post-covid-19 condition in previously hospitalised children using the isaric global follow-up protocol: a prospective cohort study. Eur Respir J 59:2101341. 10.1183/13993003.01341-2021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8576804</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34210789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paprocki J, Pawlowska M, Sutkowy P, Piechocki J, Wozniak A (2020) Evaluation of oxidative stress in patients with difficult-to-heal skin wounds treated with hyperbaric oxygen. Oxid Med Cell Longev 2020:1835352. 10.1155/2020/1835352</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7415099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32802258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paredes S, Cantillo S, Candido KD, Knezevic NN (2019) An association of serotonin with pain disorders and its modulation by estrogens. Int J Mol Sci. 10.3390/ijms20225729</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6888666</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31731606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patterson BK, Francisco EB, Yogendra R, Long E, Pise A, Rodrigues H, Hall E, Herrera M, Parikh P, Guevara-Coto J, Triche TJ, Scott P, Hekmati S, Maglinte D, Chang X, Mora-Rodriguez RA, Mora J (2021) Persistence of sars cov-2 s1 protein in cd16&#x2009;+&#x2009;monocytes in post-acute sequelae of covid-19 (pasc) up to 15 months post-infection. Front Immunol 12:746021. 10.3389/fimmu.2021.746021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8784688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35082777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patterson BK, Guevara-Coto J, Yogendra R, Francisco EB, Long E, Pise A, Rodrigues H, Parikh P, Mora J, Mora-Rodr&#xed;guez RA (2021) Immune-based prediction of covid-19 severity and chronicity decoded using machine learning. Front Immunol. 10.3389/fimmu.2021.700782</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8273732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34262570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pena-Villalobos I, Casanova-Maldonado I, Lois P, Prieto C, Pizarro C, Lattus J, Osorio G, Palma V (2018) Hyperbaric oxygen increases stem cell proliferation, angiogenesis and wound-healing ability of wj-mscs in diabetic mice. Front Physiol 9:995. 10.3389/fphys.2018.00995</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6078002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30104981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phetsouphanh C, Darley DR, Wilson DB, Howe A, Munier CML, Patel SK, Juno JA, Burrell LM, Kent SJ, Dore GJ, Kelleher AD, Matthews GV (2022) Immunological dysfunction persists for 8 months following initial mild-to-moderate sars-cov-2 infection. Nat Immunol 23:210&#x2013;216. 10.1038/s41590-021-01113-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35027728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pisoschi AM, Pop A (2015) The role of antioxidants in the chemistry of oxidative stress: a review. Eur J Med Chem 97:55&#x2013;74. 10.1016/j.ejmech.2015.04.040</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25942353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pons S, Fodil S, Azoulay E, Zafrani L (2020) The vascular endothelium: the cornerstone of organ dysfunction in severe sars-cov-2 infection. Crit Care 24:353. 10.1186/s13054-020-03062-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7296907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32546188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poudel AN, Zhu S, Cooper N, Roderick P, Alwan N, Tarrant C, Ziauddeen N, Yao GL (2021) Impact of covid-19 on health-related quality of life of patients: a structured review. PLoS ONE 16:e0259164. 10.1371/journal.pone.0259164</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8553121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34710173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poulose N, Raju R (2015) Sirtuin regulation in aging and injury. Biochim Biophys Acta 1852:2442&#x2013;2455. 10.1016/j.bbadis.2015.08.017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4682052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26303641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proal AD, VanElzakker MB (2021) Long covid or post-acute sequelae of covid-19 (pasc): an overview of biological factors that may contribute to persistent symptoms. Front Microbiol 12:698169. 10.3389/fmicb.2021.698169</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8260991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34248921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puelles VG, Lutgehetmann M, Lindenmeyer MT, Sperhake JP, Wong MN, Allweiss L, Chilla S, Heinemann A, Wanner N, Liu S, Braun F, Lu S, Pfefferle S, Schroder AS, Edler C, Gross O, Glatzel M, Wichmann D, Wiech T, Kluge S, Pueschel K, Aepfelbacher M, Huber TB (2020) Multiorgan and renal tropism of sars-cov-2. N Engl J Med 383:590&#x2013;592. 10.1056/NEJMc2011400</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7240771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32402155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren X, Wen W, Fan X, Hou W, Su B, Cai P, Li J, Liu Y, Tang F, Zhang F, Yang Y, He J, Ma W, He J, Wang P, Cao Q, Chen F, Chen Y, Cheng X, Deng G, Deng X, Ding W, Feng Y, Gan R, Guo C, Guo W, He S, Jiang C, Liang J, Li YM, Lin J, Ling Y, Liu H, Liu J, Liu N, Liu SQ, Luo M, Ma Q, Song Q, Sun W, Wang G, Wang F, Wang Y, Wen X, Wu Q, Xu G, Xie X, Xiong X, Xing X, Xu H, Yin C, Yu D, Yu K, Yuan J, Zhang B, Zhang P, Zhang T, Zhao J, Zhao P, Zhou J, Zhou W, Zhong S, Zhong X, Zhang S, Zhu L, Zhu P, Zou B, Zou J, Zuo Z, Bai F, Huang X, Zhou P, Jiang Q, Huang Z, Bei JX, Wei L, Bian XW, Liu X, Cheng T, Li X, Zhao P, Wang FS, Wang H, Su B, Zhang Z, Qu K, Wang X, Chen J, Jin R, Zhang Z (2021) Covid-19 immune features revealed by a large-scale single-cell transcriptome atlas. Cell 184:1895&#x2013;1913. e1819</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7857060</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33657410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reusch N, De Domenico E, Bonaguro L, Schulte-Schrepping J, Bassler K, Schultze JL, Aschenbrenner AC (2021) Neutrophils in covid-19. Front Immunol 12:652470. 10.3389/fimmu.2021.652470</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8027077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33841435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richard L, Bruno SJC, Nancy M, Frick (1998) Parallels between post-polio fatigue and chronic fatigue syndrome a common pathophysiology. Am J Med 105:66&#x2013;73</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9790485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robbins T, Gonevski M, Clark C, Baitule S, Sharma K, Magar A, Patel K, Sankar S, Kyrou I, Ali A, Randeva HS (2021) Hyperbaric oxygen therapy for the treatment of long covid: early evaluation of a highly promising intervention. Clin Med 21:e629&#x2013;e632. 10.7861/clinmed.2021-0462</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8806311</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34862223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rocco M, Antonelli M, Letizia V, Alampi D, Spadetta G, Passariello M, Conti G, Serio P, Gasparetto A (2001) Lipid peroxidation, circulating cytokine and endothelin 1 levels in healthy volunteers undergoing hyperbaric oxygenation. Minerva Anestesiol 67:393&#x2013;400. https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/11382829
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11382829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rocha Santos Passos F, Heimfarth L, Souza Monteiro B, Bani Corr&#xea;a C, Rodrigues de Moura T, Antunes de Souza Ara&#xfa;jo A, Ricardo Martins-Filho P, Quintans-J&#xfa;nior LJ, de Souza Siqueira Quintans J (2022) Oxidative stress and inflammatory markers in patients with covid-19: potential role of rage, hmgb1, gfap and cox-2 in disease severity. Int Immunopharmacol 104:108502. 10.1016/j.intimp.2021.108502</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8730710</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35063743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubin R (2020) As their numbers grow, covid-19 long haulers stump experts. JAMA 324:1381&#x2013;1383. 10.1001/jama.2020.17709</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32965460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salamanna F, Maglio M, Landini MP, Fini M (2020) Body localization of ace-2: on the trail of the keyhole of sars-cov-2. Front Med (Lausanne) 7:594495. 10.3389/fmed.2020.594495</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7744810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33344479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salhanick SD, Belikoff B, Orlow D, Holt D, Reenstra W, Buras JA (2006) Hyperbaric oxygen reduces acetaminophen toxicity and increases hif-1&#x3b1; expression. Acad Emerg Med 13:707&#x2013;714. 10.1197/j.aem.2006.01.029</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16636360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salmon-Ceron D, Slama D, De Broucker T, Karmochkine M, Pavie J, Sorbets E, Etienne N, Batisse D, Spiridon G, Baut VL, Meritet JF, Pichard E, Canoui-Poitrine F, collaboration AC-r, (2021) Clinical, virological and imaging profile in patients with prolonged forms of covid-19: A cross-sectional study. J Infect 82:e1&#x2013;e4. 10.1016/j.jinf.2020.12.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7833274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33285216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santos SAD, Andrade DRJ (2017) Hif-1alpha and infectious diseases: a new frontier for the development of new therapies. Rev Inst Med Trop Sao Paulo 59:e92. 10.1590/S1678-9946201759092</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5738998</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29267600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Satoh A, Cynthia, Rensing N, Cliften P, David, Erik, Kelvin, Imai S-I (2013) Sirt1 extends life span and delays aging in mice through the regulation of nk2 homeobox 1 in the dmh and lh. Cell Metabol 18:416&#x2013;430. 10.1016/j.cmet.2013.07.013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3794712</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24011076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schurink B, Roos E, Radonic T, Barbe E, Bouman CSC, de Boer HH, de Bree GJ, Bulle EB, Aronica EM, Florquin S, Fronczek J, Heunks LMA, de Jong MD, Guo L, du Long R, Lutter R, Molenaar PCG, Neefjes-Borst EA, Niessen HWM, van Noesel CJM, Roelofs J, Snijder EJ, Soer EC, Verheij J, Vlaar APJ, Vos W, van der Wel NN, van der Wal AC, van der Valk P, Bugiani M (2020) Viral presence and immunopathology in patients with lethal covid-19: a prospective autopsy cohort study. Lancet Microbe 1:e290&#x2013;e299. 10.1016/S2666-5247(20)30144-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7518879</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33015653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Semenza G (2007) Life with oxygen. Sience 318:62&#x2013;64</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17916722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Semenza GL (2011) Hypoxia-inducible factor 1: Regulator of mitochondrial metabolism and mediator of ischemic preconditioning. Biochim Biophys Acta 1813:1263&#x2013;1268. 10.1016/j.bbamcr.2010.08.006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3010308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20732359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Semenza GL (2014) Hypoxia-inducible factor 1 and cardiovascular disease. Annu Rev Physiol 76:39&#x2013;56. 10.1146/annurev-physiol-021113-170322</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4696033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23988176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Semenza GL (2014) Oxygen sensing, hypoxia-inducible factors, and disease pathophysiology. Annu Rev Pathol 9:47&#x2013;71. 10.1146/annurev-pathol-012513-104720</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23937437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Semenza GL (2010) Arteriosclerosis. Thromb Vasc Biol 30:648&#x2013;652. 10.1161/atvbaha.108.181644</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2841694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19729615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serebrovska ZO, Chong EY, Serebrovska TV, Tumanovska LV, Xi L (2020) Hypoxia, hif-1alpha, and covid-19: from pathogenic factors to potential therapeutic targets. Acta Pharmacol Sin 41:1539&#x2013;1546. 10.1038/s41401-020-00554-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7588589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33110240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serocki M, Bartoszewska S, Janaszak-Jasiecka A, Ochocka RJ, Collawn JF, Bartoszewski R (2018) Mirnas regulate the hif switch during hypoxia: a novel therapeutic target. Angiogenesis 21:183&#x2013;202. 10.1007/s10456-018-9600-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5878208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29383635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah AS, Wong AW, Hague CJ, Murphy DT, Johnston JC, Ryerson CJ, Carlsten C (2021) A prospective study of 12-week respiratory outcomes in covid-19-related hospitalisations. Thorax 76:402&#x2013;404. 10.1136/thoraxjnl-2020-216308</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33273023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen XR, Geng R, Li Q, Chen Y, Li SF, Wang Q, Min J, Yang Y, Li B, Jiang RD, Wang X, Zheng XS, Zhu Y, Jia JK, Yang XL, Liu MQ, Gong QC, Zhang YL, Guan ZQ, Li HL, Zheng ZH, Shi ZL, Zhang HL, Peng K, Zhou P (2022) Ace2-independent infection of t lymphocytes by sars-cov-2. Signal Transduct Target Ther 7:83. 10.1038/s41392-022-00919-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8914143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35277473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siewiera J, Brodaczewska K, Jermakow N, Lubas A, Klos K, Majewska A, Kot J (2022) Effectiveness of hyperbaric oxygen therapy in sars-cov-2 pneumonia: the primary results of a randomised clinical trial. J Clin Med. 10.3390/jcm12010008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9820955</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36614808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siewiera J, Brodaczewska K, Jermakow N, Lubas A, K&#x142;os K, Majewska A, Kot J (2022) Effectiveness of hyperbaric oxygen therapy in sars-cov-2 pneumonia: the primary results of a randomised clinical trial. J Clin Med 12:8. 10.3390/jcm12010008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9820955</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36614808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh AK, Kumar MP, Sharma V (2021) Hyperbaric oxygen therapy for ulcerative colitis: conflicting evidence from randomized trials. Eur J Gastroenterol Hepatol 33:e1110. 10.1097/MEG.0000000000002233</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35048686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomon T (2021) Neurological infection with sars-cov-2 - the story so far. Nat Rev Neurol 17:65&#x2013;66. 10.1038/s41582-020-00453-w</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7789883</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33414554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Somaa F (2021) A review of the application of hyperbaric oxygen therapy in alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. J Alzheimers Dis 81:1361&#x2013;1367. 10.3233/JAD-210157</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33935095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soriano JB, Murthy S, Marshall JC, Relan P, Diaz JV, Condition WHOCCDWGoP-C-, (2021) A clinical case definition of post-covid-19 condition by a delphi consensus. Lancet Infect Dis. 10.1016/S1473-3099(21)00703-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8691845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34951953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stahlberg M, Reistam U, Fedorowski A, Villacorta H, Horiuchi Y, Bax J, Pitt B, Matskeplishvili S, Luscher TF, Weichert I, Thani KB, Maisel A (2021) Post-covid-19 tachycardia syndrome: a distinct phenotype of post-acute covid-19 syndrome. Am J Med. 10.1016/j.amjmed.2021.07.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8356730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34390682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun L, Marti HH, Veltkamp R (2008) Hyperbaric oxygen reduces tissue hypoxia and hypoxia-inducible factor-1 alpha expression in focal cerebral ischemia. Stroke 39:1000&#x2013;1006. 10.1161/STROKEAHA.107.490599</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18239183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sureda A, Batle JM, Martorell M, Capo X, Tejada S, Tur JA, Pons A (2016) Antioxidant response of chronic wounds to hyperbaric oxygen therapy. PLoS ONE 11:e0163371. 10.1371/journal.pone.0163371</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5031445</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27654305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tao X, Garron T, Agrawal AS, Algaissi A, Peng BH, Wakamiya M, Chan TS, Lu L, Du L, Jiang S, Couch RB, Tseng CT (2016) Characterization and demonstration of the value of a lethal mouse model of middle east respiratory syndrome coronavirus infection and disease. J Virol 90:57&#x2013;67. 10.1128/JVI.02009-15</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4702581</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26446606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taquet M, Sillett R, Zhu L, Mendel J, Camplisson I, Dercon Q, Harrison PJ (2022) Neurological and psychiatric risk trajectories after sars-cov-2 infection: an analysis of 2-year retrospective cohort studies including 1 284 437 patients. Lancet Psychiatry 9:815&#x2013;827. 10.1016/S2215-0366(22)00260-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9385200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35987197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tenforde MW, Devine OJ, Reese HE, Silk BJ, Iuliano AD, Threlkel R, Vu QM, Plumb ID, Cadwell BL, Rose C, Steele MK, Briggs-Hagen M, Ayoubkhani D, Pawelek P, Nafilyan V, Saydah SH, Bertolli J (2022) Point prevalence estimates of activity-limiting long-term symptoms among U.S.&#xa0;adults &gt;/=1 month after reported sars-cov-2 infection. J Infect Dis. 10.1093/infdis/jiac281</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9047160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35385875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Theilen H, Schrock H, Kuschinsky W (1994) Gross persistence of capillary plasma perfusion after middle cerebral artery occlusion in the rat brain. J Cereb Blood Flow Metab 14,:1055&#x2013;1061</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7929648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torp KD, Murphy-Lavoie HM (2022) Acute traumatic ischemia hyperbaric evaluation and treatment. Statpearls, Treasure Island</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30725699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Townsend L, Dyer AH, Jones K, Dunne J, Mooney A, Gaffney F, O&#x2019;Connor L, Leavy D, O&#x2019;Brien K, Dowds J, Sugrue JA, Hopkins D, Martin-Loeches I, Ni Cheallaigh C, Nadarajan P, McLaughlin AM, Bourke NM, Bergin C, O&#x2019;Farrelly C, Bannan C, Conlon N (2020) Persistent fatigue following sars-cov-2 infection is common and independent of severity of initial infection. PLoS ONE 15:e0240784. 10.1371/journal.pone.0240784</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7652254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33166287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tziolos N-R, Ioannou P, Baliou S, Kofteridis DP (2023) Long covid-19 pathophysiology: what do we know so far? Microorganisms 11:2458. 10.3390/microorganisms11102458</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10609046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37894116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Untari N, Kusumastuti K, Suryokusumo G, Sudiana IK (2023) Hyperbaric oxygen therapy improves recovery at acute motor axonal neuropathy case. J Neurosci Rural Pract 14:145&#x2013;148. 10.25259/JNRP_9_2022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9944315</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36891088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Borst B, Peters JB, Brink M, Schoon Y, Bleeker-Rovers CP, Schers H, van Hees HWH, van Helvoort H, van den Boogaard M, van der Hoeven H, Reijers MH, Prokop M, Vercoulen J, van den Heuvel M (2021) Comprehensive health assessment 3 months after recovery from acute coronavirus disease 2019 (covid-19). Clin Infect Dis 73:e1089&#x2013;e1098. 10.1093/cid/ciaa1750</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7717214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33220049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venkatraman A, Edlow BL, Immordino-Yang MH (2017) The brainstem in emotion: a review. Front Neuroanat 11:15. 10.3389/fnana.2017.00015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5343067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28337130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vickery A, Willis P, Powell J, Beach B, Cameron A, Johnson E, Smith R (2023) The impact of covid-19 lockdown measures on older residents&#x2019; social connections and everyday wellbeing within housing schemes that provide care and support in England and Wales. J Aging Stud. 10.1016/j.jaging.2023.101126</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9986125</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37268374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walker EP, Tadi P (2022) Neuroanatomy, nucleus raphe. Statpearls, Treasure Island</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31335079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang EY, Mao T, Klein J, Dai Y, Huck JD, Jaycox JR, Liu F, Zhou T, Israelow B, Wong P, Coppi A, Lucas C, Silva J, Oh JE, Song E, Perotti ES, Zheng NS, Fischer S, Campbell M, Fournier JB, Wyllie AL, Vogels CBF, Ott IM, Kalinich CC, Petrone ME, Watkins AE, Obaid A, Moore AJ, Casanovas-Massana A, Lu-Culligan A, Nelson A, Nunez A, Martin A, Geng B, Odio CD, Harden CA, Todeasa C, Jensen C, Kim D, McDonald D, Shepard D, Courchaine E, White EB, Silva E, Kudo E, Deiuliis G, Rahming H, Park H-J, Matos I, Nouws J, Valdez J, Lim J, Rose K-A, Anastasio K, Brower K, Glick L, Sharma L, Sewanan L, Knaggs L, Minasyan M, Batsu M, Kuang M, Nakahata M, Linehan M, Askenase MH, Simonov M, Smolgovsky M, Sonnert N, Naushad N, Vijayakumar P, Martinello R, Datta R, Handoko R, Bermejo S, Prophet S, Bickerton S, Velazquez S, Rice T, Khoury-Hanold W, Peng X, Yang Y, Cao Y, Strong Y, Dela Cruz C, Farhadian SF, Schulz WL, Ma S, Grubaugh ND, Ko AI, Iwasaki A, Ring AM (2021) Diverse functional autoantibodies in patients with covid-19. Nature 595:283&#x2013;288. 10.1038/s41586-021-03631-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34010947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ward JP (2008) Oxygen sensors in context. Biochim Biophys Acta 1777:1&#x2013;14. 10.1016/j.bbabio.2007.10.010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18036551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitaker M, Elliott J, Chadeau-Hyam M, Riley S, Darzi A, Cooke G, Ward H, Elliott P (2022) Persistent covid-19 symptoms in a community study of 606,434 people in England. Nat Commun. 10.1038/s41467-022-29521-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9005552</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35413949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wichmann D, Sperhake JP, Lutgehetmann M, Steurer S, Edler C, Heinemann A, Heinrich F, Mushumba H, Kniep I, Schroder AS, Burdelski C, de Heer G, Nierhaus A, Frings D, Pfefferle S, Becker H, Bredereke-Wiedling H, de Weerth A, Paschen HR, Sheikhzadeh-Eggers S, Stang A, Schmiedel S, Bokemeyer C, Addo MM, Aepfelbacher M, Puschel K, Kluge S (2020) Autopsy findings and venous thromboembolism in patients with covid-19: a prospective cohort study. Ann Intern Med 173:268&#x2013;277. 10.7326/M20-2003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7240772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32374815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams MK, Crawford CA, Zapolski TC, Hirsh AT, Stewart JC (2024) Longer-term mental health consequences of covid-19 infection: moderation by race and socioeconomic status. Int J Behav Med. 10.1007/s12529-024-10271-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38396274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wise LM, Xi Y, Purdy JG (2021) Hypoxia-inducible factor 1alpha (hif1alpha) suppresses virus replication in human cytomegalovirus infection by limiting kynurenine synthesis. mBio. 10.1128/mBio.02956-20</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8092273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33758082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yachou Y, El Idrissi A, Belapasov V, Ait Benali S (2020) Neuroinvasion, neurotropic, and neuroinflammatory events of sars-cov-2: understanding the neurological manifestations in covid-19 patients. Neurol Sci 41:2657&#x2013;2669. 10.1007/s10072-020-04575-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7385206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32725449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamamoto T, Sadoshima J (2011) Protection of the heart against ischemia/reperfusion by silent information regulator 1. Trends Cardiovasc Med 21:27&#x2013;32. 10.1016/j.tcm.2012.01.005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3326382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22498017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yelin D, Wirtheim E, Vetter P, Kalil AC, Bruchfeld J, Runold M, Guaraldi G, Mussini C, Gudiol C, Pujol M, Bandera A, Scudeller L, Paul M, Kaiser L, Leibovici L (2020) Long-term consequences of covid-19: Research needs. Lancet Infect Dis 20:1115&#x2013;1117. 10.1016/S1473-3099(20)30701-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7462626</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32888409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeo E-J (2019) Hypoxia and aging. Exp Mol Med 51:1&#x2013;15. 10.1038/s12276-019-0233-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6586788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31221957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yong SJ (2021) Persistent brainstem dysfunction in long-covid: a hypothesis. ACS Chem Neurosci 12:573&#x2013;580. 10.1021/acschemneuro.0c00793</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33538586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yong SJ, Tong T, Chew J, Lim WL (2019) Antidepressive mechanisms of probiotics and their therapeutic potential. Front Neurosci 13:1361. 10.3389/fnins.2019.01361</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6971226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32009871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaidi AK, Dehgani-Mobaraki P (2024) Chapter six&#x2014;long covid. In: Zaidi AK (ed) Progress in molecular biology and translational science. Academic Press, Cambridge, pp 113&#x2013;125</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38237983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zant AEFX, Paulson CP, Wright JK (2022) Hyperbaric oxygen treatment of lingering covid-19 symptoms. UHM 49:333&#x2013;339</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36001566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang HN, Dai Y, Zhang CH, Omondi AM, Ghosh A, Khanra I, Chakraborty M, Yu XB, Liang J (2020) Sirtuins family as a target in endothelial cell dysfunction: implications for vascular ageing. Biogerontology 21:495&#x2013;516. 10.1007/s10522-020-09873-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32285331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Z, Daugherty WP, Sun D, Levasseur JE, Altememi N, Hamm RJ, Rockswold GL, Bullock MR (2007) Protection of mitochondrial function and improvement in cognitive recovery in rats treated with hyperbaric oxygen following lateral fluid-percussion injury. J Neurosurg 106:687&#x2013;694. 10.3171/jns.2007.106.4.687</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17432723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zilberman-Itskovich S, Catalogna M, Sasson E, Elman-Shina K, Hadanny A, Lang E, Finci S, Polak N, Fishlev G, Korin C, Shorer R, Parag Y, Sova M, Efrati S (2022) Hyperbaric oxygen therapy improves neurocognitive functions and symptoms of post-covid condition: Randomized controlled trial. Sci Rep 12:11252. 10.1038/s41598-022-15565-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9276805</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35821512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zochodne DW (2012) The challenges and beauty of peripheral nerve regrowth. J Peripher Nerv Syst 17:1&#x2013;18. 10.1111/j.1529-8027.2012.00378.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22462663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>