<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39559556</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1178-7074</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><PubDate><Year>2024</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of general medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Gen Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A Narrative Review of Impact of Incentive Spirometer Respiratory Training in Long COVID.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>5233</StartPage><EndPage>5246</EndPage><MedlinePgn>5233-5246</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2147/IJGM.S492772</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Long COVID refers to symptoms that appear 3 months after initial infection with severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2), the causative virus of Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19), and last for at least 2 months, not attributable to other diagnoses. This health issue significantly burdens patients' quality of life, the economy, and society. Improving the af-termath of COVID-19 is a crucial global health issue in the post-pandemic era. According to current results, it is evident that developing a simple, low-cost respiratory training method that can be easily used at home by themselves with long Coronavirus disease 2019 symptoms (long COVID) is an important and urgent issue. The incentive spirometer is widely used in physical, speech, and respiratory therapy, as well as in preventing postoperative pulmonary infections and improving sputum clearance. However, to date, the role of incentive spirometer respiratory training in long COVID symptoms is still limited. In this literature review is presented to explore the effectiveness of incentive spirometer respiratory training in alleviating symptoms among individuals recovering from long COVID. We also compile non-invasive assessment methods, with the aim to enable individuals to undergo training and assessments conveniently at home or in the community. In this review, a literature review approach was utilized to explore the effectiveness of incentive spirometer intervention in alleviating long-term COVID symptoms. This study is to synthesize the findings of articles published during January 2019 and December 2023 retrieved from PubMed/CINAHL/MEDLINE/ Google Scholar without re-strictions on study type. We ultimately identified seven articles and have summarized similar past studies. This review could contribute to improving symptoms related to long COVID by incentive spirometer respiratory training and serve as practical reference material for clinical medical staff and provide insights for healthcare policymakers in de-veloping guidelines for future research directions, clinical guidance, and educational strategies in the context of nursing care.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 Chen and Hsieh.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Yao-Hsiang</ForeName><Initials>YH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing, Tri-Service General Hospital Songshan Branch, Taipei City, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nursing, National Taipei University of Nursing and Health Sciences, Taipei City, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hsieh</LastName><ForeName>Yu-Shan</ForeName><Initials>YS</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7726-3819</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nursing, National Taipei University of Nursing and Health Sciences, Taipei City, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>New Zealand</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Gen Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101515487</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1178-7074</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">incentive Spirometer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">incentive spirometer respiratory training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">respiratory training</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest in this work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39559556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11570525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/IJGM.S492772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">492772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Taiwan Centers for Disease Control. National Severe Special Infectious Pneumonia (Case Definition Version Prior to March 19, 2023) Domestic and Imported Case Statistics Table. Ministry of Health and Welfare. 2023. Available from: https://nidss.cdc.gov.tw/nndss/disease?id=19CoV.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>TaiwanMinistryofHealthandWelfare. Hospital and Clinic statistics. 2023. Available from: https://www.mohw.gov.tw/mp2.html.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tufts J, Guan N, Zemedikun DT, et al. The cost of primary care consultations associated with long COVID in non-hospitalised adults: a retrospective cohort study using UK primary care data. BMC Prim Care. 2023;24(1):245. doi:10.1186/s12875-023-02196-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12875-023-02196-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10662438</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37986044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koumpias AM, Schwartzman D, Fleming O. Long-haul COVID: healthcare utilization and medical expenditures 6 months post-diagnosis. BMC Health Serv Res. 2022;22(1):1010. doi:10.1186/s12913-022-08387-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-022-08387-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9358916</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35941617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koc HC, Xiao J, Liu W, Li Y, Chen G. Long COVID and its Management. Int J Biol Sci. 2022;18(12):4768&#x2013;4780. doi:10.7150/ijbs.75056</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7150/ijbs.75056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9305273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35874958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cabrera Martimbianco AL, Pacheco RL, Bagattini &#xc2;M, Riera R. Frequency, signs and symptoms, and criteria adopted for long COVID-19: a systematic review. Int J Clin Pract. 2021;75(10):e14357. doi:10.1111/ijcp.14357</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ijcp.14357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8236920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33977626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jimeno-Almaz&#xe1;n A, Pallar&#xe9;s JG, Buend&#xed;a-Romero &#xc1;, et al. Post-COVID-19 Syndrome and the Potential Benefits of Exercise. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18(10):5329. doi:10.3390/ijerph18105329</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph18105329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8156194</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34067776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gale GD, Sanders DE. The Bartlett-Edwards incentive spirometer: a preliminary assessment of its use in the prevention of atelectasis after cardio-pulmonary bypass. Can Anaesth Soc J. 1977;24(3):408&#x2013;416. doi:10.1007/BF03005115</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF03005115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">871945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hristara-Papadopoulou A, Tsanakas J, Diomou G, Papadopoulou O. Current devices of respiratory physiotherapy. Hippokratia. 2008;12(4):211&#x2013;220.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2580042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19158964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>OM L, Buwalda T, Blair M, et al. Impact of Long COVID on health and quality of life. HRB Open Res. 2022;5:31. doi:10.12688/hrbopenres.13516.1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12688/hrbopenres.13516.1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9440374</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36101871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Kessel SAM, Olde Hartman TC, Lucassen P, van Jaarsveld CHM. Post-acute and long-COVID-19 symptoms in patients with mild diseases: a systematic review. Fam Pract. 2022;39(1):159&#x2013;167. doi:10.1093/fampra/cmab076</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/fampra/cmab076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8414057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34268556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, Assaf GS, McCorkell L, et al. Characterizing long COVID in an international cohort: 7 months of symptoms and their impact. EClinicalMedicine. 2021;38:101019. doi:10.1016/j.eclinm.2021.101019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eclinm.2021.101019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8280690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34308300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma Y, Deng J, Liu Q, Du M, Liu M, Liu J. Long-Term Consequences of COVID-19 at 6 Months and Above: a Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19(11):1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9180091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35682448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed I, Mustafaoglu R, Yeldan I, Yasaci Z, Erhan B. Effect of Pulmonary Rehabilitation Approaches on Dyspnea, Exercise Capacity, Fatigue, Lung Functions, and Quality of Life in Patients With COVID-19: a Systematic Review and Meta-analysis. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2022;103(10):2051&#x2013;2062. doi:10.1016/j.apmr.2022.06.007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apmr.2022.06.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9334878</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35908659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poon ET, Zheng C, Wong SH. Effect of Wearing Surgical Face Masks During Exercise: does Intensity Matter? Front Physiol. 2021;12:775750. doi:10.3389/fphys.2021.775750</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2021.775750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8662700</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34899397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toor H, Kashyap S, Yau A, et al. Efficacy of Incentive Spirometer in Increasing Maximum Inspiratory Volume in an Out-Patient Setting. Cureus. 2021;13(10):e18483. doi:10.7759/cureus.18483</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.18483</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8569649</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34754645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Troosters T, Janssens W, Demeyer H, Rabinovich RA. Pulmonary rehabilitation and physical interventions. Eur Respir Rev. 2023;32(168):220222. doi:10.1183/16000617.0222-2022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/16000617.0222-2022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10245142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37286219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nopp S, Moik F, Klok FA, et al. Outpatient Pulmonary Rehabilitation in Patients with Long COVID Improves Exercise Capacity, Functional Status, Dyspnea, Fatigue, and Quality of Life. Respiration. 2022;101(6):593&#x2013;601. doi:10.1159/000522118</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000522118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9059007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35203084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu K, Zhang W, Yang Y, Zhang J, Li Y, Chen Y. Respiratory rehabilitation in elderly patients with COVID-19: a randomized controlled study. Complement Ther Clin Pract. 2020;39:101166. doi:10.1016/j.ctcp.2020.101166</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ctcp.2020.101166</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7118596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32379637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsutsui M, Gerayeli F, Sin DD. Pulmonary Rehabilitation in a Post-COVID-19 World: telerehabilitation as a New Standard in Patients with COPD. Int J Chron Obstruct Pulmon Dis. 2021;16:379&#x2013;391. doi:10.2147/COPD.S263031</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/COPD.S263031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7903963</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33642858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng B, Daines L, Han Q, et al. Prevalence, risk factors and treatments for post-COVID-19 breathlessness: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Eur Respir Rev. 2022;31(166):220071. doi:10.1183/16000617.0071-2022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/16000617.0071-2022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9724798</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36323418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santino TA, Chaves GS, Freitas DA, Fregonezi GA, Mendon&#xe7;a KM. Breathing exercises for adults with asthma. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2020;3(3):Cd001277. doi:10.1002/14651858.CD001277.pub4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD001277.pub4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7096190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32212422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones M, Harvey A, Marston L, O&#x2019;Connell NE. Breathing exercises for dysfunctional breathing/hyperventilation syndrome in adults. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2013;2013(5):Cd009041. doi:10.1002/14651858.CD009041.pub2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD009041.pub2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11379427</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23728685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh SJ, Baldwin MM, Daynes E, et al. Respiratory sequelae of COVID-19: pulmonary and extrapulmonary origins, and approaches to clinical care and rehabilitation. Lancet Respir Med. 2023;11(8):709&#x2013;725. doi:10.1016/S2213-2600(23)00159-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2213-2600(23)00159-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10198676</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37216955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobs SS, Krishnan JA, Lederer DJ, et al. Home Oxygen Therapy for Adults with Chronic Lung Disease: an Official American Thoracic Society Clinical Practice Guideline. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2020;202(10):e121&#x2013;e41. doi:10.1164/rccm.202009-3608ST</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1164/rccm.202009-3608ST</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7667898</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33185464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eltorai AEM, Baird GL, Eltorai AS, et al. Perspectives on Incentive Spirometry Utility and Patient Protocols. Respir Care. 2018;63(5):519&#x2013;531. doi:10.4187/respcare.05872</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4187/respcare.05872</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29362216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sum SK, Peng YC, Yin SY, et al. Using an incentive spirometer reduces pulmonary complications in patients with traumatic rib fractures: a randomized controlled trial. Trials. 2019;20(1):797. doi:10.1186/s13063-019-3943-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13063-019-3943-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6937666</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31888765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seyller H, Gottlieb M, Colla J. A breath of fresh air: the role of incentive spirometry in the treatment of COVID-19. Am J Emergency Med. 2021;48:369. doi:10.1016/j.ajem.2021.01.084</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajem.2021.01.084</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8500986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33558097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia AC, Sarenas J. Blowing in the Wind: use of Incentive Spirometry in Preventing Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome for Patients with Moderate COVID. Eur Respir J. 2022;60(suppl 66):268.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Srinivasan V, Kandakurti PK, Alagesan J, et al. Efficacy of pursed lip breathing with bhastrika pranayama vs incentive spirometry in rehabilitating post Covid 19 follow up-a randomized control study. Turkish J Physiother Rehab. 2021;32:1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abodonya AM, Abdelbasset WK, Awad EA, Elalfy IE, Salem HA, Elsayed SH. Inspiratory muscle training for recovered COVID-19 patients after weaning from mechanical ventilation: a pilot control clinical study. Medicine. 2021;100(13):e25339. doi:10.1097/MD.0000000000025339</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000025339</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8021337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33787632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gudivada KK, Tikka SK, Bonthala Y, Miryala SK, Ch RP, Garre S. Association Between Post-COVID Pulmonary Dysfunction and New-Onset Anxiety and Depression and the Impact of Incentive Spirometer-Based Exercises. Prim Care Companion CNS Disord. 2023;25(5). doi:10.4088/PCC.23m03490</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4088/PCC.23m03490</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37816252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsu W-L, Chang Y-W, Horng Y-S, Hsu Y-T, Wu P-S. The successful rehabilitation of a 75-year-old female with debilitating long COVID: a case report. JFormos Med Assoc. 2022;121(7):1342&#x2013;1347. doi:10.1016/j.jfma.2022.01.016</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jfma.2022.01.016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8800380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35105498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kusumawardani RI, Tinduh D, Poerwandari D, Melaniani S, IA M. The effectiveness of incentive spirometry exercise on pulmonary function in COVID-19 survivors: a randomized controlled trial study. Bali Medical Journal. 2023;12(1):539&#x2013;544. doi:10.15562/bmj.v12i1.3956</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15562/bmj.v12i1.3956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suharti A, Nur Hidayati E, Yusviani H. Comparative effect of incentive spirometry and diaphragm breathing to functional capacity in COVID-19 patient in an isolated ward. Bali Medical Journal. 2022;11(3):1415&#x2013;1419. doi:10.15562/bmj.v11i3.3579</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15562/bmj.v11i3.3579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Curci C, Negrini F, Ferrillo M, et al. Functional outcome after inpatient rehabilitation in postintensive care unit COVID-19 patients: findings and clinical implications from a real-practice retrospective study. Eur J Phys Rehabil Med. 2021;57(3):443&#x2013;450. doi:10.23736/S1973-9087.20.06660-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.23736/S1973-9087.20.06660-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33393278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garre KKGSKTYBSKMRPa S. Association Between Post-COVID Pulmonary Dysfunction and New-Onset Anxiety and Depression and the Impact of Incentive Spirometer-Based Exercises. The Primary Care Companion. 2023;25:479272.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37816252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seyller H, Gottlieb M, Colla J. The Role of Incentive Spirometry for Patients with COVID-19. Am J Emerg Med. 2021;47:292&#x2013;293. doi:10.1016/j.ajem.2021.05.034</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajem.2021.05.034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8123532</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34020843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao HM, Xie YX, Wang C. Recommendations for respiratory rehabilitation in adults with coronavirus disease 2019. Chin Med J. 2020;133(13):1595&#x2013;1602. doi:10.1097/CM9.0000000000000848</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CM9.0000000000000848</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7470013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32251002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lazzeri M, Lanza A, Bellini R, et al. Respiratory physiotherapy in patients with COVID-19 infection in acute setting: a Position Paper of the Italian Association of Respiratory Physiotherapists (ARIR). Monaldi Arch Chest Dis. 2020;90(1). doi:10.4081/monaldi.2020.1285.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4081/monaldi.2020.1285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32236089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rehabilitation. CAoRMRRCoCAoRMCRGoCSoPMa. Recommendations for respiratory rehabilitation of coronavirus disease 2019 in adult. Zhonghua jie he he hu xi za zhi = Zhonghua jiehe he huxi zazhi = Chinese journal of tuberculosis and respiratory diseases. 2020;43(4):308&#x2013;314. doi:10.3760/cma.j.cn112147-20200228-00206</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3760/cma.j.cn112147-20200228-00206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32294814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheehy LM. Considerations for Postacute Rehabilitation for Survivors of COVID-19. JMIR Public Health Surveill. 2020;6(2):e19462. doi:10.2196/19462</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/19462</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7212817</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32369030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rizvi A, Macedo P, Babawale L, et al. Hemoglobin Is a Vital Determinant of Arterial Oxygen Content in Hypoxemic Patients with Pulmonary Arteriovenous Malformations. Ann Am Thorac Soc. 2017;14(6):903&#x2013;911. doi:10.1513/AnnalsATS.201611-872OC</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1513/AnnalsATS.201611-872OC</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28267932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klok FA, Boon G, Barco S, et al. The Post-COVID-19 Functional Status scale: a tool to measure functional status over time after COVID-19. Eur Respir J. 2020;56(1):2001494. doi:10.1183/13993003.01494-2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/13993003.01494-2020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7236834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32398306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Machado FVC, Meys R, Delbressine JM, et al. Construct validity of the Post-COVID-19 Functional Status Scale in adult subjects with COVID-19. Health Qual Life Outcomes. 2021;19(1):40. doi:10.1186/s12955-021-01691-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12955-021-01691-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7856622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33536042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benkalfate N, Eschapasse E, Georges T, et al. Evaluation of the Post-COVID-19 Functional Status (PCFS) Scale in a cohort of patients recovering from hypoxemic SARS-CoV-2 pneumonia. BMJ Open Respir Res. 2022;9(1). doi:10.1136/bmjresp-2021-001136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjresp-2021-001136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8915286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35264326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agarwala P, Salzman SH. Six-Minute Walk Test: clinical Role, Technique, Coding, and Reimbursement. Chest. 2020;157(3):603&#x2013;611. doi:10.1016/j.chest.2019.10.014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chest.2019.10.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7609960</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31689414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferioli M, Prediletto I, Bensai S, et al. The role of 6MWT in Covid-19 follow up. Eur Respir J. 2021;58(suppl 65):OA4046.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellet RN, Adams L, Morris NR. The 6-minute walk test in outpatient cardiac rehabilitation: validity, reliability and responsiveness--a systematic review. Physiotherapy. 2012;98(4):277&#x2013;286. doi:10.1016/j.physio.2011.11.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.physio.2011.11.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23122432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Liu X, Tong Z. Can inspiratory muscle training benefit patients with COVID-19? A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Med Virol. 2023;95(8):e28956. doi:10.1002/jmv.28956</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmv.28956</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37503550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams MT, Lewthwaite H, Paquet C, et al. Dyspnoea-12 and Multidimensional Dyspnea Profile: systematic Review of Use and Properties. J Pain Symptom Manage. 2022;63(1):e75&#x2013;e87. doi:10.1016/j.jpainsymman.2021.06.023</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpainsymman.2021.06.023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34273524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi TCM, Chan LLY, Tsang HC, et al. Adaptation and validation of the Chinese version of Dyspnoea-12 scale in individuals with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Clin Respir J. 2021;15(10):1081&#x2013;1087. doi:10.1111/crj.13411</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/crj.13411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8518647</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34145767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banzett RB, O&#x2019;Donnell CR, Guilfoyle TE, et al. Multidimensional Dyspnea Profile: an instrument for clinical and laboratory research. Eur Respir J. 2015;45(6):1681&#x2013;1691. doi:10.1183/09031936.00038914</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/09031936.00038914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4450151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25792641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banzett RB, Moosavi SH. Measuring dyspnoea: new multidimensional instruments to match our 21st century understanding. Eur Respir J. 2017;49(3):1602473. doi:10.1183/13993003.02473-2016</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/13993003.02473-2016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5524133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28254768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amado Diago CA, Puente Maestu L, Abascal Bolado B, et al. Translation and Validation of the Multidimensional Dyspnea-12 Questionnaire. Arch Bronconeumol. 2018;54(2):74&#x2013;78. doi:10.1016/j.arbres.2017.08.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arbres.2017.08.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29122333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishimura K, Oga T, Nakayasu K, et al. Comparison between tools for measuring breathlessness: cross-sectional validation of the Japanese version of the Dyspnoea-12. Clin Respir J. 2021;15(11):1201&#x2013;1209. doi:10.1111/crj.13427</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/crj.13427</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34288426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milne KM, Cowan J, Schaeffer MR, et al. Exercise responses and mental health symptoms in COVID-19 survivors with dyspnoea. ERJ Open Res. 2023;9(3):606&#x2013;2022. doi:10.1183/23120541.00606-2022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/23120541.00606-2022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10258874</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37337509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Philip KEJ, Owles H, McVey S, et al. An online breathing and wellbeing programme (ENO Breathe) for people with persistent symptoms following COVID-19: a parallel-group, single-blind, randomised controlled trial. Lancet Respir Med. 2022;10(9):851&#x2013;862. doi:10.1016/S2213-2600(22)00125-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2213-2600(22)00125-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9045747</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35489367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez-Gerez JJ, Saavedra-Hernandez M, Anarte-Lazo E, Bernal-Utrera C, Perez-Ale M, Rodriguez-Blanco C. Short-Term Effects of a Respiratory Telerehabilitation Program in Confined COVID-19 Patients in the Acute Phase: a Pilot Study. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18(14):7511. doi:10.3390/ijerph18147511</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph18147511</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8306449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34299962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tran V-T, Riveros C, Clepier B, et al. Development and Validation of the Long Coronavirus Disease (COVID) Symptom and Impact Tools: a Set of Patient-Reported Instruments Constructed From Patients Lived Experience. Clinl Infect Dis. 2021;74(2):278&#x2013;287. doi:10.1093/cid/ciab352</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cid/ciab352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8135558</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33912905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A, Sehgal K, Gupta A, et al. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nat Med. 2021;27(4):601&#x2013;615. doi:10.1038/s41591-021-01283-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-021-01283-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8893149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33753937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soriano JB, Murthy S, Marshall JC, Relan P, Diaz JV. A clinical case definition of post-COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus. Lancet Infect Dis. 2022;22(4):e102&#x2013;e7. doi:10.1016/S1473-3099(21)00703-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1473-3099(21)00703-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8691845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34951953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO. WHO Guidelines Approved by the Guidelines Review Committee. Clinical Management of COVID-19: Living Guideline. Geneva: World Health Organization; 2022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35917394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>