<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39522688</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2090-1224</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of advanced research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Adv Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Brain-targeted autoimmunity is strongly associated with Long COVID and its chronic fatigue syndrome as well as its affective symptoms.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S2090-1232(24)00530-7</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jare.2024.11.011</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Autoimmune responses contribute to the pathophysiology of Long COVID, affective symptoms and myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To examine whether Long COVID, and its accompanying affective symptoms and CFS are associated with immunoglobulin (Ig)A/IgM/IgG directed at neuronal proteins including myelin basic protein (MBP), myelin oligodendrocyte glycoprotein (MOG), synapsin, &#x3b1;&#xa0;+&#xa0;&#x3b2;-tubulin, neurofilament protein (NFP), cerebellar protein-2 (CP2), and the blood-brain-barrier-brain-damage (BBD) proteins claudin-5 and S100B.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">IgA/IgM/IgG to the above neuronal proteins, human herpes virus-6 (HHV-6) and Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome Coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) were measured in 90 Long COVID patients and 90 healthy controls, while C-reactive protein (CRP), and advanced oxidation protein products (AOPP) in association with affective and CFS ratings were additionally assessed in a subgroup thereof.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Long COVID is associated with significant increases in IgG directed at tubulin (IgG-tubulin), MBP, MOG and synapsin; IgM-MBP, MOG, CP2, synapsin and BBD; and IgA-CP2 and synapsin. IgM-SARS-CoV-2 and IgM-HHV-6 antibody titers were significantly correlated with IgA/IgG/IgM-tubulin and -CP2, IgG/IgM-BBD, IgM-MOG, IgA/IgM-NFP, and IgG/IgM-synapsin. Binary logistic regression analysis shows that IgM-MBP and IgG-MBP are the best predictors of Long COVID. Multiple regression analysis shows that IgG-MOG, CRP and AOPP explain together 41.7&#xa0;% of the variance in the severity of CFS. Neural network analysis shows that IgM-synapsin, IgA-MBP, IgG-MOG, IgA-synapsin, IgA-CP2, IgG-MBP and CRP are the most important predictors of affective symptoms due to Long COVID with a predictive accuracy of r&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.801.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Brain-targeted autoimmunity contributes significantly to the pathogenesis of Long COVID and the severity of its physio-affective phenome.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024. Published by Elsevier B.V.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Almulla</LastName><ForeName>Abbas F</ForeName><Initials>AF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sichuan Provincial Center for Mental Health, Sichuan Provincial People's Hospital, School of Medicine, University of Electronic Science and Technology of China, Chengdu 610072, China; Key Laboratory of Psychosomatic Medicine, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences, Chengdu, 610072, China; Department of Psychiatry, Faculty of Medicine, Chulalongkorn University, and King Chulalongkorn Memorial Hospital, the Thai Red Cross Society, Bangkok, Thailand; Medical Laboratory Technology Department, College of Medical Technology, The Islamic University, Najaf, Iraq.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maes</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sichuan Provincial Center for Mental Health, Sichuan Provincial People's Hospital, School of Medicine, University of Electronic Science and Technology of China, Chengdu 610072, China; Key Laboratory of Psychosomatic Medicine, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences, Chengdu, 610072, China; Department of Psychiatry, Faculty of Medicine, Chulalongkorn University, and King Chulalongkorn Memorial Hospital, the Thai Red Cross Society, Bangkok, Thailand; Cognitive Impairment and Dementia Research Unit, Faculty of Medicine, Chulalongkorn University, Bangkok, Thailand; Department of Psychiatry, Medical University of Plovdiv, Plovdiv, Bulgaria; Research Center, Medical University of Plovdiv, Plovdiv, Bulgaria; Kyung Hee University, 26 Kyungheedae-ro, Dongdaemun-gu, Seoul 02447, Korea. Electronic address: dr.michaelmaes@hotmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Bo</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Faculty of Medicine, Chulalongkorn University, and King Chulalongkorn Memorial Hospital, the Thai Red Cross Society, Bangkok, Thailand; Medical Laboratory Technology Department, College of Medical Technology, The Islamic University, Najaf, Iraq.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Al-Hakeim</LastName><ForeName>Hussein K</ForeName><Initials>HK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, College of Science, University of Kufa, Kufa, Iraq.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vojdani</LastName><ForeName>Aristo</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Immunosciences Lab, Inc., Los Angeles, CA 90035, USA; Cyrex Laboratories, LLC, Phoenix, AZ 85034, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Egypt</Country><MedlineTA>J Adv Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101546952</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2090-1224</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Affective disorders</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chronic fatigue syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Depression</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neuroimmune</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Oxidative stress</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39522688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jare.2024.11.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2090-1232(24)00530-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>