<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38144169</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1178-6469</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><PubDate><Year>2023</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of tryptophan research : IJTR</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Tryptophan Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Urine Metabolite Analysis to Identify Pathomechanisms of Long COVID: A Pilot Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>11786469231220781</StartPage><MedlinePgn>11786469231220781</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">11786469231220781</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/11786469231220781</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Around 10% of people who had COVID-9 infection suffer from persistent symptoms such as fatigue, dyspnoea, chest pain, arthralgia/myalgia, sleep disturbances, cognitive dysfunction and impairment of mental health. Different underlying pathomechanisms appear to be involved, in particular inflammation, alterations in amino acid metabolism, autonomic dysfunction and gut dysbiosis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">As routine tests are often inconspicuous in patients with Long COVID (LC), similarly to patients suffering from myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS), accessible biomarkers indicating dysregulation of specific pathways are urgently needed to identify underlying pathomechanisms and enable personalized medicine treatment. Within this pilot study we aimed to proof traceability of altered metabolism by urine analysis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PATIENTS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Urine metabolome analyses were performed to investigate the metabolic signature of patients with LC (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;25; 20 women, 5 men) in comparison to healthy controls (Ctrl, n&#x2009;=&#x2009;8; 7 women, 1 man) and individuals with ME/CFS (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;8; 2 women, 6 men). Concentrations of neurotransmitter precursors tryptophan, phenylalanine and their downstream metabolites, as well as their association with symptoms (fatigue, anxiety and depression) in the patients were examined.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS AND CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Phenylalanine levels were significantly lower in both the LC and ME/CFS patient groups when compared to the Ctrl group. In many LC patients, the concentrations of downstream metabolites of tryptophan and tyrosine, such as serotonin, dopamine and catecholamines, deviated from the reference ranges. Several symptoms (sleep disturbance, pain or autonomic dysfunction) were associated with certain metabolites. Patients experiencing fatigue had lower levels of kynurenine, phenylalanine and a reduced kynurenine to tryptophan ratio (Kyn/Trp). Lower concentrations of gamma-aminobutyric acid (GABA) and higher activity of kynurenine 3-monooxygenase (KMO) were observed in patients with anxiety. Conclusively, our results suggest that amino acid metabolism and neurotransmitter synthesis is disturbed in patients with LC and ME/CFS. The identified metabolites and their associated dysregulations could serve as potential biomarkers for elucidating underlying pathomechanisms thus enabling personalized treatment strategies for these patient populations.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2023.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Taenzer</LastName><ForeName>Maja</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine II, Medical University of Innsbruck, Innsbruck, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>L&#xf6;ffler-Ragg</LastName><ForeName>Judith</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine II, Medical University of Innsbruck, Innsbruck, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schroll</LastName><ForeName>Andrea</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine II, Medical University of Innsbruck, Innsbruck, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Monfort-Lanzas</LastName><ForeName>Pablo</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2589-3960</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Medical Biochemistry, Biocenter, Medical University of Innsbruck, Innsbruck, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Bioinformatics, Biocenter, Medical University of Innsbruck, Innsbruck, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Engl</LastName><ForeName>Sabine</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine II, Medical University of Innsbruck, Innsbruck, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weiss</LastName><ForeName>G&#xfc;nter</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine II, Medical University of Innsbruck, Innsbruck, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brigo</LastName><ForeName>Natascha</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine II, Medical University of Innsbruck, Innsbruck, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kurz</LastName><ForeName>Katharina</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine II, Medical University of Innsbruck, Innsbruck, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Tryptophan Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101513378</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1178-6469</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">IFN-gamma mediated pathway</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long-COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fatigue</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">gut dysbiosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">urine metabolites</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The author(s) declared the following potential conflicts of interest with respect to the research, authorship, and/or publication of this article: The authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as potential conflicts of interest. Analyses performed by Biovis Diagnostik were paid for by grant GZ 75759 (Land Tirol, see above).</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38144169</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10748708</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/11786469231220781</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1177_11786469231220781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Sudre C, Murray B, Varsavsky T, et al.. Attributes and predictors of long COVID. Nat Med. 2021;27:626-631.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7611399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33692530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Huang L, Wang Y. Expression of concern: 6-month consequences of COVID-19 in patients discharged from hospital: a cohort study. Lancet. 2021; 401:90-232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9691145</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36436530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venkatesan P. NICE guideline on long COVID. Lancet Respir Med. 2021;9:129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7832375</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33453162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holmes GP, Kaplan JE, Stewart JA, et al.. A cluster of patients with a chronic mononucleosis-like syndrome. Is Epstein-Barr virus the cause? JAMA. 1987;257:2297-2302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3033337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellmann-Weiler R, Schroecksnadel K, Holzer C, et al.. IFN-gamma mediated pathways in patients with fatigue and chronic active Epstein Barr virus-infection. J Affect Disord. 2008;108:171-176.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17945348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fukuda K, Straus SE, Hickie I, et al.. The chronic fatigue syndrome: a comprehensive approach to its definition and study. International Chronic Fatigue Syndrome Study Group. Ann Intern Med. 1994;121:953-959.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7978722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bj&#xf8;rklund G, Dadar M, Pivina L, et al.. Environmental, neuro-immune, and neuro-oxidative stress interactions in chronic fatigue syndrome. Mol Neurobiol. 2020;57:4598-4607.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32761353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kedor C, Freitag H, Meyer-Arndt L, et al.. A prospective observational study of post-COVID-19 chronic fatigue syndrome following the first pandemic wave in Germany and biomarkers associated with symptom severity. Nat Commun. 2022;13:5104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9426365</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36042189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Underhill R, Baillod R. Myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome: organic disease or psychosomatic illness? A re-examination of the royal free epidemic of 1955. Medicina. 2020;57:12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7824095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33375343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wojcik W, Armstrong D, Kanaan R. Is chronic fatigue syndrome a neurological condition? A survey of UK neurologists. J Psychosom Res. 2011;70:573-574.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21624581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, McCorkell L, Vogel JM, Topol EJ. Long COVID: major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2023;21:133-146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9839201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36639608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rass V, Beer R, Schiefecker AJ, et al.. Neurological outcome and quality of life 3 months after COVID-19: a prospective observational cohort study. Eur J Neurol. 2021;28:3348-3359.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8250725</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33682276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sonnweber T, Boehm A, Sahanic S, et al.. Persisting alterations of iron homeostasis in COVID-19 are associated with non-resolving lung pathologies and poor patients&#x2019; performance: a prospective observational cohort study. Respir Res. 2020;21:276.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7575703</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33087116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lorusso L, Mikhaylova SV, Capelli E, et al.. Immunological aspects of chronic fatigue syndrome. Autoimmun Rev. 2009;8:287-291.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18801465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brenu EW, van Driel ML, Staines DR, et al.. Immunological abnormalities as potential biomarkers in chronic fatigue syndrome/myalgic encephalomyelitis. J Transl Med. 2011;9:81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3120691</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21619669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sotzny F, Blanco J, Capelli E, et al..; European Network on ME/CFS (EUROMENE). Myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome - evidence for an autoimmune disease. Autoimmun Rev. 2018;17:601-609.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29635081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wirth K, Scheibenbogen C. A unifying hypothesis of the pathophysiology of myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS): recognitions from the finding of autoantibodies against &#xdf;2-adrenergic receptors. Autoimmun Rev. 2020;19:102527.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32247028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dorottya Nagy-Szakal B, Mishra N, Che X, et al.. Fecal metagenomic profiles in subgroups of patients with myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome. 10.1186/s40168-017-0261-y. Microbiome. 2017;5:1-17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5405467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28441964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naviaux RK, Naviaux JC, Li K, et al.. Reply to Vogt et al.: Metabolomics and chronic fatigue syndrome. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2016;113:E7142-E7143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5135342</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27810963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giloteaux L, Goodrich JK, Walters WA, Levine SM, Ley RE, Hanson MR. Reduced diversity and altered composition of the gut microbiome in individuals with myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome. Microbiome. 2016; 4:1-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4918027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27338587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corbitt M, Campagnolo N, Staines D, Marshall-Gradisnik S. A systematic review of probiotic interventions for gastrointestinal symptoms and irritable bowel syndrome in chronic fatigue syndrome/myalgic encephalomyelitis (CFS/ME). Probiotics Antimicrob Proteins. 2018;10:466-477.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29464501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Navaneetharaja N, Griffiths V, Wileman T, Carding SR. A role for the intestinal microbiota and virome in myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS)? J Clin Med. 2016;5:55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4929410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27275835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komaroff A, Lipkin W. ME/CFS and Long COVID share similar symptoms and biological abnormalities: road map to the literature. Front Med. 2023;10:1187163.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10278546</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37342500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liptak P, Duricek M, Rosolanka R, et al.. Gastrointestinal sequalae months after severe acute respiratory syndrome corona virus 2 infection: a prospective, observational study. Eur J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2022;34:925-932.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35913778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leblhuber F, Ehrlich D, Steiner K, et al.. The immunopathogenesis of Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease is related to the composition of gut Microbiota. Nutrients. 2021; 13:361.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7912578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33504065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roy Sarkar S, Banerjee S. Gut microbiota in neurodegenerative disorders. J Neuroimmunol. 2019;328:98-104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30658292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naviaux RK, Naviaux JC, Li K, et al.. Metabolic features of chronic fatigue syndrome. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2016;113:E5472-E5480.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5027464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27573827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandarano AH, Maya J, Giloteaux L, et al.. Myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome patients exhibit altered T cell metabolism and cytokine associations. J Clin Investig. 2020;130:1491-1505.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7269566</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31830003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maes M, Twisk FN, Kubera M, Ringel K. Evidence for inflammation and activation of cell-mediated immunity in myalgic encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome (ME/CFS): increased interleukin-1, tumor necrosis factor-&#x3b1;, PMN-elastase, lysozyme and neopterin. J Affect Disord. 2012;136:933-939.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21975140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurz K, Fiegl M, Holzner B, et al.. Fatigue in patients with lung cancer is related with accelerated tryptophan breakdown. PLoS One. 2012;7:e36956.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3353990</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22615854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schroecksnadel K, Zangerle R, Bellmann-Weiler R, et al.. Indoleamine-2, 3-dioxygenase and other interferon-gamma-mediated pathways in patients with human immunodeficiency virus infection. Curr Drug Metab. 2007;8:225-236.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17430111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lanser L, Kink P, Egger EM, et al.. Inflammation-induced tryptophan breakdown is related with anemia, fatigue, and depression in cancer. Front Immunol. 2020;11:249.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7047328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32153576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kink P, Egger EM, Lanser L, et al.. Immune activation and anemia are associated with decreased quality of life in patients with solid tumors. J Clin Med. 2020;9:3248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7601852</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33053619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fooladi F, Sohrabi Z, Akbarzadeh M. Association of Quality of life with serum phenylalanine level and socioeconomic status in patients with phenylketonuria: a review. Int J Nutr Food Sci. 2019;4:109-112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cryan JF, Dinan TG. Mind-altering microorganisms: the impact of the gut microbiota on brain and behaviour. Nat Rev Neurosci. 2012;13:701-712.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22968153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Mahony SM, Clarke G, Borre YE, Dinan TG, Cryan JF. Serotonin, tryptophan metabolism and the brain-gut-microbiome axis. Behav Brain Res. 2015;277:32-48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25078296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang H, Ling Z, Zhang Y, et al.. Altered fecal microbiota composition in patients with major depressive disorder. Brain Behav Immun. 2015;48:186-194.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25882912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H, Chen Y, Wang Z, et al.. Implications of gut Microbiota in Neurodegenerative Diseases. Front Immunol. 2022;13:785644.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8882587</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35237258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Obermoser K, Brigo N, Schroll A, et al.. Positive effects of probiotic therapy in patients with post-infectious fatigue. Metabolites. 2023;13:639.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10221065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37233680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sampson TR, Mazmanian SK. Control of brain development, function, and behavior by the microbiome. Cell Host Microbe. 2015;17:565-576.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4442490</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25974299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de J R, De-Paula V, Forlenza AS, Forlenza OV. Relevance of gutmicrobiota in cognition, behaviour and Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. Pharmacol Res. 2018;136:29-34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30138667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westfall S, Lomis N, Kahouli I, et al.. Microbiome, probiotics and neurodegenerative diseases: deciphering the gut brain axis. Cell Mol Life Sci. 2017;74: 3769-3787.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11107790</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28643167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gostner JM, Becker K, Kurz K, Fuchs D. Disturbed amino acid metabolism in HIV: association with neuropsychiatric symptoms. Front Psychiatry. 2015;6:97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4500866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26236243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gierk B, Kohlmann S, Kroenke K, et al.. The somatic symptom scale-8 (SSS-8): a brief measure of somatic symptom burden. JAMA Intern Med. 2014;174:399-407.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24276929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toussaint A, H&#xfc;sing P, Kohlmann S, L&#xf6;we B. Detecting DSM-5 somatic symptom disorder: criterion validity of the Patient Health Questionnaire-15 (PHQ-15) and the somatic symptom scale-8 (SSS-8) in combination with the somatic symptom disorder - B Criteria Scale (SSD-12). Psychol Med. 2020;50:324-333.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30729902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosolanka R, Liptak P, Baranovicova E, et al.. Changes in the urine metabolomic profile in patients recovering from severe COVID-19. Metabolites. 2023;13:364.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10058594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36984804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maes M, Kubera M, Stoyanova K, Leunis JC. The reification of the clinical diagnosis of myalgic encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome (ME/CFS) as an immune and oxidative stress disorder: construction of a data-driven nomothethic network and exposure of ME/CFS subgroups. Curr Top Med Chem. 2021;21: 1488-1499.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34315375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellmann-Weiler R, Lanser L, Burkert F, et al.. Neopterin predicts disease severity in hospitalized patients with COVID-19. Open Forum Infect Dis. 2021;8:ofaa521.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7665702</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33442554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schroecksnadel K, Walter RB, Weiss G, et al.. Association between plasma thiols and immune activation marker neopterin in stable coronary heart disease. Clin Chem Lab Med. 2008;46:648-654.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18839466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Capuron L, Schroecksnadel S, F&#xe9;art C, et al.. Chronic low-grade inflammation in elderly persons is associated with altered tryptophan and tyrosine metabolism: role in neuropsychiatric symptoms. Biol Psychiatry. 2011;70:175-182.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21277567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang A, Fuchs D, Widner B, et al.. Serum tryptophan decrease correlates with immune activation and impaired quality of life in colorectal cancer. Br J Cancer. 2002;86:1691-1696.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2375406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12087451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behan WM, McDonald M, Darlington LG, Stone TW. Oxidative stress as a mechanism for quinolinic acid-induced hippocampal damage: protection by melatonin and deprenyl. Br J Pharmacol. 1999;128:1754-1760.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1571800</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10588931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guillemin GJ, Brew BJ. Implications of the kynurenine pathway and quinolinic acid in Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. Redox Rep. 2002;7:199-206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12396664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guillemin GJ, Smith DG, Smythe GA, Armati PJ, Brew BJ. Expression of the kynurenine pathway enzymes in human microglia and macrophages. Adv Exp Med Biol. 2003;527:105-112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15206722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garrison AM, Parrott JM, Tu&#xf1;on A, et al.. Kynurenine pathway metabolic balance influences microglia activity: targeting kynurenine monooxygenase to dampen neuroinflammation. Psychoneuroendocrinology. 2018;94:1-10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5995655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29734055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quist-Paulsen E, Aukrust P, Kran AB, et al.. High neopterin and IP-10 levels in cerebrospinal fluid are associated with neurotoxic tryptophan metabolites in acute central nervous system infections. J Neuroinflammation. 2018;15:327.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6260858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30470234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shirai R, Sato K, Yamashita T, et al.. Neopterin counters vascular inflammation and Atherosclerosis. J Am Heart Assoc. 2018;7:e007359.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5850243</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29420219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geisler S, Lytton SD, Toan NL, et al.. Neopterin levels and Kyn/Trp ratios were significantly increased in dengue virus patients and subsequently decreased after recovery. Int J Infect Dis. 2020;91:162-168.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31821895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Benedetti F, De Amici M, Aramini L, Ruperto N, Martini A. Correlation of serum neopterin concentrations with disease activity in juvenile dermatomyositis. Arch Dis Child. 1993;69:232-235.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1029465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8215528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cavaleri D, Bartoli F, Capogrosso CA, et al.. Blood concentrations of neopterin and biopterin in subjects with depression: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Prog Neuropsychopharmacol Biol Psychiatry. 2023;120:110633.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36089162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maes M, Verkerk R, Bonaccorso S, et al.. Depressive and anxiety symptoms in the early puerperium are related to increased degradation of tryptophan into kynurenine, a phenomenon which is related to immune activation. Life Sci. 2002;71:1837-1848.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12175700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simonato M, Dall&#x2019;Acqua S, Zilli C, et al.. Tryptophan metabolites, cytokines, and fatty acid binding protein 2 in myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome. Biomedicines. 2021;9:1724.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8615774</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34829952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xf6;nig RS, Albrich WC, Kahlert CR, et al.. The gut microbiome in Myalgic Encephalomyelitis (ME)/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome (CFS). Front Immunol. 2021;12:5616.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8761622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35046929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobs E, D&#x2019;Esposito M. Estrogen shapes dopamine-dependent cognitive processes: implications for women&#x2019;s health. J Neurosci. 2011;31:5286-5293.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3089976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21471363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jard&#xed; F, Laurent MR, Kim N, et al.. Testosterone boosts physical activity in male mice via dopaminergic pathways. Sci Rep. 2018;8:957.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5772634</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29343749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>