<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39534773</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2312-0541</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>10</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>ERJ open research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>ERJ Open Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A worldwide look into long COVID-19 management: an END-COVID survey.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">00096-2024</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1183/23120541.00096-2024</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Long COVID is a heterogeneous clinical syndrome characterised by a variety of reported symptoms and signs. Its clinical management is expected to differ significantly worldwide.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A survey-based study investigating long COVID-related standard operating procedures (SOPs) has been conducted by the European Respiratory Society (ERS) END-COVID clinical research collaboration with the support of other international societies (ALAT, APSR, CHEST, ESCMID and PATS). A global analysis of the results is provided here, alongside sub-population analysis based on continents, national income levels, type of involved healthcare professional and inclusion or exclusion of paediatric patients.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="FINDINGS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">1015 healthcare professionals from 110 different countries worldwide participated in this study, the majority of them being respiratory physicians (60.6%). A dedicated long COVID programme was present in 55.4% of the investigated institutions, with hospital admission during the acute infection being the main inclusion criteria to access them. Consistent differences in long COVID-related procedures were identified among centres, mainly regarding the multidisciplinary approach, the availability of telemedicine and psychological support, the type of requested exams and the total amount of visits in the centre.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="INTERPRETATION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Long COVID management shows important differences related to geographical areas and national income levels. SOPs were significantly different when centres were managed by a pulmonologist or when paediatric patients were included.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9;The authors 2024.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nigro</LastName><ForeName>Mattia</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4735-823X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Sciences, Humanitas University, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>IRCCS Humanitas Research Hospital, Respiratory Unit, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Valenzuela</LastName><ForeName>Claudia</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0856-6290</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pulmonology Department, Hospital Universitario de La Princesa, Universidad Autonoma de Madrid, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arancibia</LastName><ForeName>Francisco</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pulmonology Department, Instituto Nacional del T&#xf3;rax, Universidad de Chile, Santiago, Chile.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cohen</LastName><ForeName>Mark</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pulmonary and Critical Care, Hospital Centro M&#xe9;dico, Guatemala.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lam</LastName><ForeName>David C L</ForeName><Initials>DCL</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0004-2660</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, School of Clinical Medicine, University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong SAR, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maves</LastName><ForeName>Ryan C</ForeName><Initials>RC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sections of Infectious Diseases and Critical Care Medicine, Wake Forest University School of Medicine, Winston-Salem, NC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rath</LastName><ForeName>Barbara</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vaccine Safety Initiative, Div. Infectious Diseases, Berlin, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Simpson</LastName><ForeName>Steven Q</ForeName><Initials>SQ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Pulmonary, Critical Care, and Sleep Medicine, University of Kansas Medical Center, Kansas City, KS, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Song</LastName><ForeName>Yuanlin</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Key Laboratory of Lung Inflammation and Injury, Shanghai Respiratory Research Institute, Department of Pulmonary Medicine, Zhongshan Hospital, Fudan University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tsiodras</LastName><ForeName>Sotirios</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National and Kapodistrian University of Athens, Athens, Greece.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University Hospital of Athens Attikon, Athens, Greece.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chalmers</LastName><ForeName>James D</ForeName><Initials>JD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Molecular and Clinical Medicine, University of Dundee, Ninewells Hospital and Medical School, Dundee, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aliberti</LastName><ForeName>Stefano</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0090-4531</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Sciences, Humanitas University, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>IRCCS Humanitas Research Hospital, Respiratory Unit, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>11</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>ERJ Open Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101671641</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2312-0541</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentIn"><RefSource>doi: 10.1183/23120541.00500-2024</RefSource></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><CoiStatement>Conflict of interest: M. Nigro has nothing to disclose. Conflict of interest: C. Valenzuela reports consulting fees from Boehringer Ingelheim, Hoffman-La Roche Ltd and BMS, and payment of honoraria for lectures, presentations, speakers&#x2019; bureaus, manuscript writing or educational events and support for attending meetings and/or travel from Boehringer Ingelheim, in the past 36 months. Conflict of interest: F. Arancibia has nothing to disclose. Conflict of interest: M. Cohen is past president of ALAT. Conflict of interest: D.C.L. Lam is president of the APSR and FIRS. Conflict of interest: R.C. Maves reports clinical trial funding to his institution from AiCuris, Sound Pharmaceuticals and GeoVax; travel funding provided for committee work as a member of the American College of Chest Physicians (CHEST) Scientific Program Committee from CHEST, the Society of Critical Care Medicine (SCCM) Scientific Program Committee from the SCCM and the American Board of Internal Medicine (ABIM) Critical Care Medicine Approval Committee from the ABIM; honoraria paid to himself for clinical trial support as a medical monitor and data safety monitoring board member from LumaBridge, and for scientific advisory panel membership from Shionogi, all in the past 36 months; and a US patent on the candidate dengue vaccine unrelated to this study; and is chair of the CHEST Disaster Response and Global Health Section, and the CHEST Rapid Response Task Force, and a member of the CHEST Scientific Program Committee (all unpaid except for official travel funding as above); chair of the SCCM FCCS Crisis Management Committee, a member of the SCCM Congress Program Committee, Co-Vice Chair of the SCCM 2025 Critical Care Congress and Designated Co-Chair of the SCCM 2026 Critical Care Congress (all unpaid except for official travel funding as above); and a member of the ABIM Critical Care Medicine Approval Committee (travel funded plus honorarium for Board service). Conflict of interest: B. Rath reports European Union funding only; support for attending meetings and/or travel for MedScape and scientific societies only; patents not pertinent to this article; participation on a data safety monitoring or advisory board for GSK COVID-19 and influenza infant clinical trials, all in the past 36 months; and is on ISIRV, ESGREV, AAP and IPA vaccination-related steering committees. Conflict of interest: S.Q. Simpson is a board member of the American College of Chest Physicians and Chair of the Board of Directors of the Sepsis Alliance. Conflict of interest: Y. Song is a board member of the American College of Chest Physicians and Chair of the Board of Directors of the Sepsis Alliance. Conflict of interest: S. Tsiodras reports grants or contracts for the European Union (EU) projects EU-RESPONSE (funded by EU Horizon 2020), EU Prevent and EU Reverse, paid to his institution in the past 36 months. Conflict of interest: J.D. Chalmers reports grants or contracts from AstraZeneca, Boehringer Ingelheim, Chiesi, Gilead Sciences, Grifols, Genentech, GlaxoSmithKline, Insmed and Novartis; and consulting fees from AstraZeneca, Boehringer Ingelheim, Chiesi, Gilead Sciences, Grifols, Genentech, GlaxoSmithKline, Insmed, Novartis, Roche, Trudell, Zambon, Janssen and Pfizer, all in the past 36 months; and is an associate editor of this journal. Conflict of interest: S. Aliberti reports grants or contracts from Insmed Inc., Chiesi, Fisher and Paykel and GSK, paid to his institution; royalties or licences from McGraw Hill, paid to himself; consulting fees from Insmed Inc., Insmed Italy, Insmed Ireland Ltd, Zambon Spa, AstraZeneca UK Ltd, AstraZeneca Pharmaceutical LP, CSL Behring GmbH, Grifols, Fondazione Internazionale Menarini, Moderna, Chiesi, MSD Italia S.r.l., Brahms, Physioassist SAS and GlaxoSmithKline Spa, paid to himself; payment or honoraria for lectures, presentations, speakers&#x2019; bureaus, manuscript writing or educational events from GlaxoSmithKline Spa, ThermoFisher Scientific, Insmed Italy, Insmed Ireland Ltd, Zambon and Fondazione Internazionale Menarini; and participation on a data safety monitoring or advisory board from Insmed Inc., Insmed Italy, AstraZeneca UK Ltd and MSD Italia S.r.l., all in the past 36 months.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39534773</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11551856</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/23120541.00096-2024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00096-2024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Chalmers JD, Crichton ML, Goeminne PC, et al. . Management of hospitalised adults with coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19): a European Respiratory Society living guideline. Eur Respir J 2021; 57: 2100048. doi:10.1183/13993003.00048-2021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/13993003.00048-2021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7947358</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33692120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soriano JB, Murthy S, Marshall JC, et al. . A clinical case definition of post-COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus. Lancet Infect Dis 2022; 22: e102&#x2013;e107. doi:10.1016/S1473-3099(21)00703-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1473-3099(21)00703-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8691845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34951953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah W, Hillman T, Playford ED, et al. . Managing the long term effects of covid-19: summary of NICE, SIGN and RCGP rapid guideline. BMJ 2021; 372: n136. doi:10.1136/bmj.n136</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.n136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33483331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayes LD, Ingram J, Sculthorpe NF. More than 100 persistent symptoms of SARS-CoV-2 (Long COVID): a scoping review. Front Med (Lausanne) 2021; 8: 750378. DOI:10.3389/fmed.2021.750378</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmed.2021.750378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8591053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34790680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, McCorkell L, Vogel JM, et al. . Long COVID: major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nat Rev Microbiol 2023; 21: 133&#x2013;146. doi:10.1038/s41579-022-00846-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41579-022-00846-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9839201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36639608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wulf Hanson S, Abbafati C, Aerts JG, et al. . Estimated global proportions of individuals with persistent fatigue, cognitive, and respiratory symptom clusters following symptomatic COVID-19 in 2020 and 2021. JAMA 2022; 328: 1604&#x2013;1615. doi:10.1001/jama.2022.18931</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2022.18931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9552043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36215063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C, Haupert SR, Zimmermann L, et al. . Global prevalence of post-coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) condition or long COVID: a meta-analysis and systematic review. J Infect Dis 2022; 226: 1593&#x2013;1607. doi:10.1093/infdis/jiac136</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/infdis/jiac136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9047189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35429399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stephenson T, Pinto Pereira SM, Shafran R, et al. . Physical and mental health 3 months after SARS-CoV-2 infection (long COVID) among adolescents in England (CLoCk): a national matched cohort study. Lancet Child Adolesc Health 2022; 6: 230&#x2013;239. doi:10.1016/S2352-4642(22)00022-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2352-4642(22)00022-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8820961</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35143770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization (WHO) . WHO Coronavirus (COVID-19) dashboard. Date last updated: 6 April 2023. Date last accessed: 27 January 2024. https://data.who.int/dashboards/covid19/cases</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pfaff ER, Madlock-Brown C, Baratta JM, et al. . Coding long COVID: characterizing a new disease through an ICD-10 lens. BMC Med 2023; 21: 58. doi:10.1186/s12916-023-02737-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12916-023-02737-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9931566</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36793086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antoniou KM, Vasarmidi E, Russell A-M, et al. . European Respiratory Society statement on long COVID follow-up. Eur Respir J 2022; 60: 2102174. doi:10.1183/13993003.02174-2021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/13993003.02174-2021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9349784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35144991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Houchen-Wolloff L, Poinasamy K, Holmes K, et al. . Joint patient and clinician priority setting to identify 10 key research questions regarding the long-term sequelae of COVID-19. Thorax 2022; 77: 717&#x2013;720. doi:10.1136/thoraxjnl-2021-218582</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/thoraxjnl-2021-218582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9209667</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35354642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valenzuela C, Nigro M, Chalmers JD, et al. . COVID-19 follow-up programmes across Europe: an ERS END-COVID CRC survey. Eur Respir J 2022; 60: 2200923. doi:10.1183/13993003.00923-2022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/13993003.00923-2022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9474896</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35863767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Bank . World Bank Country and Lending Groups. Date last accessed: 22 April 2023. https://datahelpdesk.worldbank.org/knowledgebase/articles/906519-world-bank-country-and-lending-groups</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maldonado LOV . Is Venezuela Still an Upper-Middle-Income Country? Estimating the GNI per Capita for 2015&#x2013;2021. Inter-American Development Bank (IDB). Date last accessed: 22 April 2023. https://publications.iadb.org/en/venezuela-still-upper-middle-income-country-estimating-gni-capita-2015-2021#:&#x223c;:text=Our%20findings%20reveal%20that%20Venezuela,2%2C079%20following%20an%20adjusted%20deflator.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng C, Shao W, Chen X, et al. . Real-world effectiveness of COVID-19 vaccines: a literature review and meta-analysis. Int J Infect Dis 2022; 114: 252&#x2013;260. doi:10.1016/j.ijid.2021.11.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijid.2021.11.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8595975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34800687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wise J. Covid-19: WHO urges action as 17 million long covid cases are estimated in Europe. BMJ 2022; 378: o2232. doi:10.1136/bmj.o2232</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.o2232</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36104031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H, Zang C, Xu Z, et al. . Data-driven identification of post-acute SARS-CoV-2 infection subphenotypes. Nat Med 2023; 29: 226&#x2013;235. doi:10.1038/s41591-022-02116-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-022-02116-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9873564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36456834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buvik A, Bergmo TS, Bugge E, et al. . Cost-effectiveness of telemedicine in remote orthopedic consultations: randomized controlled trial. J Med Internet Res 2019; 21: e11330. doi:10.2196/11330</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/11330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6399572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30777845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blomberg B, Mohn KG-I, Brokstad KA, et al. . Long COVID in a prospective cohort of home-isolated patients. Nat Med 2021; 27: 1607&#x2013;1613. doi:10.1038/s41591-021-01433-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-021-01433-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8440190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34163090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans RA, Leavy OC, Richardson M, et al. . Clinical characteristics with inflammation profiling of long COVID and association with 1-year recovery following hospitalisation in the UK: a prospective observational study. Lancet Respir Med 2022; 10: 761&#x2013;775. doi:10.1016/S2213-2600(22)00127-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2213-2600(22)00127-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9034855</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35472304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Wang Y, Li X, et al. . Clinical features of patients infected with 2019 novel coronavirus in Wuhan, China. The Lancet 2020; 395: 497&#x2013;506. doi:10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30183-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30183-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7159299</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31986264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Houchen-Wolloff L, Overton C, Ibbetson A, et al. . A typology of healthcare pathways after hospital discharge for adults with COVID-19: the evolution of UK services during pandemic conditions. ERJ Open Res 2023; 9: 00565-2022. doi:10.1183/23120541.00565-2022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/23120541.00565-2022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10423987</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37583962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>George PM, Barratt SL, Condliffe R, et al. . Respiratory follow-up of patients with COVID-19 pneumonia. Thorax 2020; 75: 1009&#x2013;1016. doi:10.1136/thoraxjnl-2020-215314</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/thoraxjnl-2020-215314</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32839287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>