<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39551439</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-6825</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>15</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Journal of allergy and clinical immunology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Allergy Clin Immunol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>COVID-19 in children: Evolving epidemiology, immunology, symptoms, diagnostics, treatment, post covid conditions, prevention strategies, and future directions.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0091-6749(24)01216-8</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jaci.2024.11.012</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The epidemiology of COVID-19 in children has evolved throughout the pandemic, with initially low infection rates rising significantly due to the emergence of the more transmissible Omicron variant. Adolescents, children from ethnic minorities and lower-income households, and those with obesity are at increased risk of contracting SARS-CoV-2 infection. The immune response in children leads to milder symptoms compared to adults, with fever and cough being most frequent; tough symptoms vary by SARS-CoV-2 variant and age. Diagnostic methods to confirm current or past infection include RT-PCR, rapid antigen tests and serology. Treatment is mainly supportive, with antivirals and glucocorticoids reserved for severe cases. While serious conditions like MIS-C and other post-COVID-19 conditions are rare, they require careful management. Vaccination has proven effective in reducing severe disease and protecting against post-COVID-19 conditions. Continued surveillance, including wastewater monitoring and universal or pooled testing, remains crucial for controlling community spread. Key questions remain regarding the duration and quality of immunity following re-infection or vaccination, the impact of co-infections, and optimal treatment protocols for different pediatric populations.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024. Published by Elsevier Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wurm</LastName><ForeName>Juliane</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Paediatrics, Fribourg Hospital, Fribourg, Switzerland; Department of Health Science and Medicine, University Lucerne, Lucerne, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ritz</LastName><ForeName>Nicole</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Science and Medicine, University Lucerne, Lucerne, Switzerland; Paediatric Infectious Diseases Unit, Department of Paediatrics, Children's Hospital, Cantonal Hospital Lucerne, Lucerne, Switzerland; Mycobacterial and Migrant Health Research, University Children's Hospital Basel and Department for Clinical Research, University of Basel, Basel, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zimmermann</LastName><ForeName>Petra</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Paediatrics, Fribourg Hospital, Fribourg, Switzerland; Department of Paediatrics, The University of Melbourne, Parkville, Australia; Infectious Diseases Research Group, Murdoch Children's Research Institute, Parkville, Australia; Department of Community Health, Faculty of Science and Medicine, University of Fribourg, Fribourg, Switzerland. Electronic address: petra.zimmermann@unifr.ch.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Allergy Clin Immunol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>1275002</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0091-6749</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">MIS-C</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pediatrics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">vaccination</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39551439</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaci.2024.11.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0091-6749(24)01216-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>