<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">39179099</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1534-4436</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>133</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Annals of allergy, asthma &amp; immunology : official publication of the American College of Allergy, Asthma, &amp; Immunology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Ann Allergy Asthma Immunol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Inflammatory pathways in patients with post-acute sequelae of COVID-19: The role of the clinical immunologist.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>507</StartPage><EndPage>515</EndPage><MedlinePgn>507-515</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.anai.2024.08.021</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S1081-1206(24)00533-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>As the SARS-CoV-2 pandemic progressed, some survivors noted prolonged symptoms after acute infection, termed post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC) or "long COVID." PASC is a significant clinical and public health concern that adversely affects patients' quality of life, income, and health care expenses. Moreover, PASC symptoms are highly heterogeneous, the most common being fatigue and cognitive impairment, and they likely reflect a spectrum of clinical phenotypes. The proposed role of persistent inflammation is one of leading pathophysiological theories. This review article addresses these proposed mechanisms of persistent and aberrant inflammation, their clinical evaluation, and theoretical approaches to management. A review of public databases was used to collect literature for the review. The literature supports a prominent role of persistent and aberrant inflammation as a major contributor to the symptoms of PASC. Proposed mechanisms for persistent inflammation include reactivation of latent viruses, viral persistence, loss of immunoregulatory pathways, autoimmune mechanisms, and/or mast cell dysregulation. Persistent inflammation may result in constitutional symptoms such as fatigue, brain fog, body aches, and/or organ-specific dysfunction, such as gastrointestinal dysregulation and myocardial inflammation. There are no approved or even proven therapies for PASC at this time, but some studies have identified therapeutic options that may either reduce the risk for progression to PASC or decrease symptom burden. Laboratory evaluation and therapeutic options are limited and require further investigation to establish their clinical value. A more refined definition of PASC is needed to address the wide variety of clinical presentations, pathophysiology, and therapeutic options.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 American College of Allergy, Asthma &amp; Immunology. Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Elliott</LastName><ForeName>Matthew R</ForeName><Initials>MR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The University of Mississippi Medical Center, Department of Internal Medicine, Division of Clinical Immunology, Jackson, Mississippi. Electronic address: melliott@umc.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>O'Connor</LastName><ForeName>Anna E</ForeName><Initials>AE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The University of Mississippi Medical Center, Department of Internal Medicine, Division of Clinical Immunology, Jackson, Mississippi.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Marshall</LastName><ForeName>Gailen D</ForeName><Initials>GD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The University of Mississippi Medical Center, Department of Internal Medicine, Division of Clinical Immunology, Jackson, Mississippi.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>OT2 HL161847</GrantID><Acronym>HL</Acronym><Agency>NHLBI NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>U19 AT010838</GrantID><Acronym>AT</Acronym><Agency>NCCIH NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Ann Allergy Asthma Immunol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9503580</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1081-1206</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="Y">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094024" MajorTopicYN="Y">Post-Acute COVID-19 Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007249" MajorTopicYN="Y">Inflammation</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Disclosures The authors have no conflicts of interest to report.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39179099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.anai.2024.08.021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S1081-1206(24)00533-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11575468</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS2025343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Yong SJ. Long COVID or post-COVID-19 syndrome: putative pathophysiology, risk factors, and treatments. Infect Dis (Lond). 2021. Oct;53(10):737&#x2013;754.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8146298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34024217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merad M, Blish CA, Sallusto F, Iwasaki A. The immunology and immunopathology of COVID-19. Science. 2022. Mar 11;375(6585):1122&#x2013;1127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35271343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thaweethai T, Jolley SE, Karlson EW, Levitan EB, Levy B, McComsey GA, et al.; RECOVER Consortium. Development of a Definition of Postacute Sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 Infection. JAMA. 2023. Jun 13;329(22):1934&#x2013;1946.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10214179</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37278994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Untersmayr E, Venter C, Smith P, Rohrhofer J, Ndwandwe C, Schwarze J, et al. Immune Mechanisms Underpinning Long COVID: Collegium Internationale Allergologicum Update 2024. Int Arch Allergy Immunol. 2024. Jan 22:1&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38253027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vu QM, Fitzpatrick AL, Cope JR, Bertolli J, Sotoodehnia N, West TE, et al. Estimates of Incidence and Predictors of Fatiguing Illness after SARS-CoV-2 Infection. Emerg Infect Dis. 2024. Mar;30(3):539&#x2013;547.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10902536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38407166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altmann DM, Whettlock EM, Liu S, Arachchillage DJ, Boyton RJ. The immunology of long COVID. Nat Rev Immunol. 2023. Oct;23(10):618&#x2013;634.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37433988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marshall GD Jr. The pathophysiology of postacute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC): Possible role for persistent inflammation. Asia Pac Allergy. 2023. Jun;13(2):77&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10287107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37388814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceban F, Ling S, Lui LMW, Lee Y, Gill H, Teopiz KM, et al. Fatigue and cognitive impairment in Post-COVID-19 Syndrome: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Brain Behav Immun. 2022. Mar;101:93&#x2013;135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8715665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34973396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wechsler JB, Butuci M, Wong A, Kamboj AP, Youngblood BA. Mast cell activation is associated with post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Allergy. 2022. Apr;77(4):1288&#x2013;1291.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9299596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34820848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sherif ZA, Gomez CR, Connors TJ, Henrich TJ, Reeves WB; RECOVER Mechanistic Pathway Task Force. Pathogenic mechanisms of post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection (PASC). Elife. 2023. Mar 22;12:e86002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10032659</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36947108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Novak P, Mukerji SS, Alabsi HS, Systrom D, Marciano SP, Felsenstein D, et al. Multisystem Involvement in Post-Acute Sequelae of Coronavirus Disease 19. Ann Neurol. 2022. Mar;91(3):367&#x2013;379.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9011495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34952975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vojdani A, Vojdani E, Saidara E, Maes M. Persistent SARS-CoV-2 Infection, EBV, HHV-6 and Other Factors May Contribute to Inflammation and Autoimmunity in Long COVID. Viruses. 2023. Jan 31;15(2):400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9967513</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36851614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su Y, Yuan D, Chen DG, Ng RH, Wang K, Choi J, et al. Multiple early factors anticipate post-acute COVID-19 sequelae. Cell. 2022. Mar 3;185(5):881&#x2013;895.e20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8786632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35216672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peluso MJ, Deveau TM, Munter SE, Ryder D, Buck A, Beck-Engeser G, et al. Chronic viral coinfections differentially affect the likelihood of developing long COVID. J Clin Invest. 2023. Feb 1;133(3):e163669.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9888380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36454631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zubchenko S, Kril I, Nadizhko O, Matsyura O, Chopyak V. Herpesvirus infections and post-COVID-19 manifestations: a pilot observational study. Rheumatol Int. 2022. Sep;42(9):1523&#x2013;1530.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9159383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35650445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gold JE, Okyay RA, Licht WE, Hurley DJ. Investigation of Long COVID Prevalence and Its Relationship to Epstein-Barr Virus Reactivation. Pathogens. 2021. Jun 17;10(6):763.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8233978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34204243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen B, Julg B, Mohandas S, Bradfute SB; RECOVER Mechanistic Pathways Task Force. Viral persistence, reactivation, and mechanisms of long COVID. Elife. 2023. May 4;12:e86015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10159620</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37140960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swank Z, Senussi Y, Manickas-Hill Z, Yu XG, Li JZ, Alter G, et al. Persistent Circulating Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome Coronavirus 2 Spike Is Associated With Post-acute Coronavirus Disease 2019 Sequelae. Clin Infect Dis. 2023. Feb 8;76(3):e487&#x2013;e490.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10169416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36052466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheung CCL, Goh D, Lim X, Tien TZ, Lim JCT, Lee JN, et al. Residual SARS-CoV-2 viral antigens detected in GI and hepatic tissues from five recovered patients with COVID-19. Gut. 2022. Jan;71(1):226&#x2013;229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34083386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaebler C, Wang Z, Lorenzi JCC, Muecksch F, Finkin S, Tokuyama M, et al. Evolution of antibody immunity to SARS-CoV-2. Nature. 2021. Mar;591(7851):639&#x2013;644.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8221082</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33461210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knight JS, Caricchio R, Casanova JL, Combes AJ, Diamond B, Fox SE, et al. The intersection of COVID-19 and autoimmunity. J Clin Invest. 2021. Dec 15;131(24):e154886.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8670833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34710063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang R, Yen-Ting Chen T, Wang SI, Hung YM, Chen HY, Wei CJ. Risk of autoimmune diseases in patients with COVID-19: A retrospective cohort study. EClinicalMedicine. 2023. Feb;56:101783.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9830133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36643619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Son K, Jamil R, Chowdhury A, Mukherjee M, Venegas C, Miyasaki K, et al. Circulating anti-nuclear autoantibodies in COVID-19 survivors predict long COVID symptoms. Eur Respir J. 2023. Jan 12;61(1):2200970.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9515477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36137590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang SE, Feng A, Meng W, Apostolidis SA, Mack E, Artandi M, et al. New-onset IgG autoantibodies in hospitalized patients with COVID-19. Nat Commun. 2021. Sep 14;12(1):5417.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8440763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34521836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richter AG, Shields AM, Karim A, Birch D, Faustini SE, Steadman L, et al. Establishing the prevalence of common tissue-specific autoantibodies following severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 infection. Clin Exp Immunol. 2021. Aug;205(2):99&#x2013;105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8239842</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34082475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>PHOSP-COVID Collaborative Group. Clinical characteristics with inflammation profiling of long COVID and association with 1-year recovery following hospitalisation in the UK: a prospective observational study. Lancet Respir Med. 2022. Aug;10(8):761&#x2013;775.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9034855</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35472304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cervia-Hasler C, Br&#xfc;ningk SC, Hoch T, Fan B, Muzio G, Thompson RC, et al. Persistent complement dysregulation with signs of thromboinflammation in active Long Covid. Science. 2024. Jan 19;383(6680):eadg7942.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38236961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin K, Peluso MJ, Luo X, Thomas R, Shin MG, Neidleman J, et al. Long COVID manifests with T cell dysregulation, inflammation and an uncoordinated adaptive immune response to SARS-CoV-2. Nat Immunol. 2024. Feb;25(2):218&#x2013;225.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10834368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38212464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Littlefield KM, Watson RO, Schneider JM, Neff CP, Yamada E, Zhang M, et al. SARS-CoV-2-specific T cells associate with inflammation and reduced lung function in pulmonary post-acute sequalae of SARS-CoV-2. PLoS Pathog. 2022. May 26;18(5):e1010359.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9176759</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35617421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>LaVergne SM, Dutt TS, McFann K, Baxter BA, Webb TL, Berry K, et al. Persistent CD8+ T cell proliferation and activation in COVID-19 adult survivors with post-acute sequelae: a longitudinal, observational cohort study of persistent symptoms and T cell markers. Front Immunol. 2024. Jan 23;14:1303971.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10848319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38327763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan PH, Ji J, Hsing CH, Tan R, Ji RR. Emerging Roles of Type-I Interferons in Neuroinflammation, Neurological Diseases, and Long-Haul COVID. Int J Mol Sci. 2022. Nov 19;23(22):14394.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9696119</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36430870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glynne P, Tahmasebi N, Gant V, Gupta R. Long COVID following mild SARS-CoV-2 infection: characteristic T cell alterations and response to antihistamines. J Investig Med. 2022. Jan;70(1):61&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8494538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34611034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berentschot JC, Drexhage HA, Aynekulu Mersha DG, Wijkhuijs AJM, GeurtsvanKessel CH, Koopmans MPG, et al. Immunological profiling in long COVID: overall low grade inflammation and T-lymphocyte senescence and increased monocyte activation correlating with increasing fatigue severity. Front Immunol. 2023. Oct 10;14:1254899.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10597688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37881427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan FJ, Hope CM, Masavuli MG, Lynn MA, Mekonnen ZA, Yeow AEL, et al. Long-term perturbation of the peripheral immune system months after SARS-CoV-2 infection. BMC Med. 2022. Jan 14;20(1):26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8758383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35027067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arun S, Storan A, Myers B. Mast cell activation syndrome and the link with long COVID. Br J Hosp Med (Lond). 2022. Jul 2;83(7):1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35938771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Theoharides TC, Kempuraj D. Role of SARS-CoV-2 Spike-Protein-Induced Activation of Microglia and Mast Cells in the Pathogenesis of Neuro-COVID. Cells. 2023. Feb 22;12(5):688.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10001285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36899824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu S, Suzuki Y, Takemasa E, Watanabe R, Mogi M. Mast cells promote viral entry of SARS-CoV-2 via formation of chymase/spike protein complex. Eur J Pharmacol. 2022. Sep 5;930:175169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9339018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35921955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raghavan S, Leo MD. Histamine Potentiates SARS-CoV-2 Spike Protein Entry Into Endothelial Cells. Front Pharmacol. 2022. Apr 25;13:872736.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9084361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35548336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Rhermoul FZ, Fedorowski A, Eardley P, Taraborrelli P, Panagopoulos D, Sutton R, et al. Autoimmunity in Long Covid and POTS. Oxf Open Immunol. 2023. Mar 8;4(1):iqad002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10224806</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37255928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weinstock LB, Brook JB, Walters AS, Goris A, Afrin LB, Molderings GJ. Mast cell activation symptoms are prevalent in Long-COVID. Int J Infect Dis. 2021. Nov;112:217&#x2013;226.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8459548</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34563706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allan-Blitz LT, Akbari O, Kojima N, Saavedra E, Chellamuthu P, Denny N, et al. Unique immune and inflammatory cytokine profiles may define long COVID syndrome. Clin Exp Med. 2023. Oct;23(6):2925&#x2013;2930.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10105906</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37061998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salvucci F, Codella R, Coppola A, Zacchei I, Grassi G, Anti ML, et al. Antihistamines improve cardiovascular manifestations and other symptoms of long-COVID attributed to mast cell activation. Front Cardiovasc Med. 2023. Jul 17;10:1202696.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10388239</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37529714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVID-19 rapid guideline: managing the long-term effects of COVID-19. London: National Institute for Health and Care Excellence (NICE); 2020. Dec 18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33555768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koc HC, Xiao J, Liu W, Li Y, Chen G. Long COVID and its Management. Int J Biol Sci. 2022. Jul 11;18(12):4768&#x2013;4780.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9305273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35874958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lui DTW, Lee CH, Woo YC, Hung IFN, Lam KSL. Thyroid dysfunction in COVID-19. Nat Rev Endocrinol. 2024. Feb 12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38347167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conway EM, Pryzdial ELG. Complement contributions to COVID-19. Curr Opin Hematol. 2022. Sep 1;29(5):259&#x2013;265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35852851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vlaicu SI, Tatomir A, Cuevas J, Rus V, Rus H. COVID, complement, and the brain. Front Immunol. 2023. Jul 18;14:1216457.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10391634</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37533859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valent P, Hartmann K, Bonadonna P, G&#xfc;len T, Brockow K, Alvarez-Twose I, et al. Global Classification of Mast Cell Activation Disorders: An ICD-10-CM-Adjusted Proposal of the ECNM-AIM Consortium. J Allergy Clin Immunol Pract. 2022. Aug;10(8):1941&#x2013;1950.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35623575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castells M, Butterfield J. Mast Cell Activation Syndrome and Mastocytosis: Initial Treatment Options and Long-Term Management. J Allergy Clin Immunol Pract. 2019. Apr;7(4):1097&#x2013;1106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30961835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seb&#x151;k S, Gyires K. Long COVID and possible preventive options. Inflammopharmacology. 2023. Dec;31(6):2807&#x2013;2817.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10692252</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37344737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asadi-Pooya AA, Nemati M, Shahisavandi M, Nemati H, Karimi A, Jafari A, et al. How does COVID-19 vaccination affect long-COVID symptoms? PLoS One. 2024. Feb 7;19(2):e0296680.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10849259</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38324547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian F, Chen Z, Feng Q. Nirmatrelvir-ritonavir compared with other antiviral drugs for the treatment of COVID-19 patients: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Med Virol. 2023. Apr;95(4):e28732.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37183808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-Las-Pe&#xf1;as C, Raveendran AV, Giordano R, Arendt-Nielsen L. Long COVID or Post-COVID-19 Condition: Past, Present and Future Research Directions. Microorganisms. 2023. Dec 11;11(12):2959.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10745830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38138102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharifinejad N, Sharafian S, Salekmoghadam S, Tavakol M, Qorbani M. Montelukast and Coronavirus Disease 2019: A Scoping Review. Iran J Allergy Asthma Immunol. 2021. Aug 7;20(4):384&#x2013;393.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34418892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kazama I Stabilizing mast cells by commonly used drugs: a novel therapeutic target to relieve post-COVID syndrome? Drug Discov Ther. 2020. Nov 4;14(5):259&#x2013;261.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33116043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;hlemann B, Thibeault C, Hillus D, Helbig ET, Lippert LJ, Tober-Lau P, et al. Impact of dexamethasone on SARS-CoV-2 concentration kinetics and antibody response in hospitalized COVID-19 patients: results from a prospective observational study. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2021. Oct;27(10):1520.e7&#x2013;1520.e10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8205283</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34139335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng B, Ma J, Yang Y, Shao T, Zhao B, Zeng L. Systemic Corticosteroid Administration in Coronavirus Disease 2019 Outcomes: An Umbrella Meta-Analysis Incorporating Both Mild and Pulmonary Fibrosis-Manifested Severe Disease. Front Pharmacol. 2021. May 26;12:670170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8187793</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34122093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagner C, Griesel M, Mikolajewska A, Metzendorf MI, Fischer AL, Stegemann M, et al. Systemic corticosteroids for the treatment of COVID-19: Equity-related analyses and update on evidence. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2022. Nov 17;11(11):CD014963.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9670242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36385229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan Sui Ko A, Candellier A, Mercier M, Joseph C, Carette H, Basille D, et al. No Impact of Corticosteroid Use During the Acute Phase on Persistent Symptoms Post-COVID-19. Int J Gen Med. 2022. Aug 18;15:6645&#x2013;6651.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9394663</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36003084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bikle DD. Vitamin D Regulation of Immune Function. Curr Osteoporos Rep. 2022. Jun;20(3):186&#x2013;193.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9065668</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35507293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomaa AA, Abdel-Wadood YA, Thabet RH, Gomaa GA. Pharmacological evaluation of vitamin D in COVID-19 and long COVID-19: recent studies confirm clinical validation and highlight metformin to improve VDR sensitivity and efficacy. Inflammopharmacology. 2024. Feb;32(1):249&#x2013;271.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10907442</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37957515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrelli F, Oldani S, Borgonovo K, Cabiddu M, Dognini G, Ghilardi M, et al. Vitamin D3 and COVID-19 Outcomes: An Umbrella Review of Systematic Reviews and Meta-Analyses. Antioxidants (Basel). 2023. Jan 22;12(2):247.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9952713</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36829806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>di Filippo L, Frara S, Nannipieri F, Cotellessa A, Locatelli M, Rovere Querini P, et al. Low Vitamin D Levels Are Associated With Long COVID Syndrome in COVID-19 Survivors. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2023. Sep 18;108(10):e1106&#x2013;e1116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10505553</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37051747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen KY, Lin CK, Chen NH. Effects of vitamin D and zinc deficiency in acute and long COVID syndrome. J Trace Elem Med Biol. 2023. Dec;80:127278.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37566973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun T, Liu J, Xie C, Yang J, Zhao L, Yang J. Metformin attenuates diabetic renal injury via the AMPK-autophagy axis. Exp Ther Med. 2021. Jun;21(6):578.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8027752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33850550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bramante CT, Buse JB, Liebovitz DM, Nicklas JM, Puskarich MA, Cohen K, et al. Outpatient treatment of COVID-19 and incidence of post-COVID-19 condition over 10 months (COVID-OUT): a multicentre, randomised, quadruple-blind, parallel-group, phase 3 trial. Lancet Infect Dis. 2023. Oct;23(10):1119&#x2013;1129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11259948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37302406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin A, Lupfer C, Amen R. Sodium Pyruvate Nasal Spray Reduces the Severity of Nasal Inflammation and Congestion in Patients with Allergic Rhinitis. J Aerosol Med Pulm Drug Deliv. 2022. Dec;35(6):291&#x2013;295.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9807276</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35960504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nadler R Sodium Pyruvate Inhalation for COVID-19 Long Hauler Symptoms &#x2013; An Effective and Inexpensive Treatment. J Immunol. 2022. May; 208 (1_Supplement): 125.25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paterniti I, Cordaro M, Campolo M, Siracusa R, Cornelius C, Navarra M, et al. Neuroprotection by association of palmitoylethanolamide with luteolin in experimental Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease models: the control of neuroinflammation. CNS Neurol Disord Drug Targets. 2014;13(9):1530&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25106636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cordaro M, Impellizzeri D, Paterniti I, Bruschetta G, Siracusa R, De Stefano D, et al. Neuroprotective Effects of Co-UltraPEALut on Secondary Inflammatory Process and Autophagy Involved in Traumatic Brain Injury. J Neurotrauma. 2016. Jan 1;33(1):132&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25046306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siracusa R, Impellizzeri D, Cordaro M, Crupi R, Esposito E, Petrosino S, et al. Anti-Inflammatory and Neuroprotective Effects of Co-UltraPEALut in a Mouse Model of Vascular Dementia. Front Neurol. 2017. Jun 6;8:233.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5460147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28634464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu B, Gong M, Xiang Y, Qu S, Zhu H, Ye D. Mechanism and treatment of olfactory dysfunction caused by coronavirus disease 2019. J Transl Med. 2023. Nov 17;21(1):829.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10657033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37978386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Stadio A, D&#x2019;Ascanio L, Vaira LA, Cantone E, De Luca P, Cingolani C, et al. Ultramicronized Palmitoylethanolamide and Luteolin Supplement Combined with Olfactory Training to Treat Post-COVID-19 Olfactory Impairment: A Multi-Center Double-Blinded Randomized Placebo-Controlled Clinical Trial. Curr Neuropharmacol. 2022;20(10):2001&#x2013;2012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9886808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35450527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Stadio A, Gallina S, Cocuzza S, De Luca P, Ingrassia A, Oliva S, et al. Treatment of COVID-19 olfactory dysfunction with olfactory training, palmitoylethanolamide with luteolin, or combined therapy: a blinded controlled multicenter randomized trial. Eur Arch Otorhinolaryngol. 2023. Nov;280(11):4949&#x2013;4961.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10562315</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37380908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Capra AP, Ardizzone A, Crupi L, Calapai F, Campolo M, Cuzzocrea S, et al. Efficacy of Palmitoylethanolamide and Luteolin Association on Post-Covid Olfactory Dysfunction: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis of Clinical Studies. Biomedicines. 2023. Aug 3;11(8):2189.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10452638</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37626685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pirro M, Ferri L, Piccioni L, Bellucci AM, Bartolucci F, Russo A, et al. What Is the Role of Palmitoylethanolamide Co-Ultramicronized with Luteolin on the Symptomatology Reported by Patients Suffering from Long COVID? A Retrospective Analysis Performed by a Group of General Practitioners in a Real-Life Setting. Nutrients. 2023. Aug 24;15(17):3701.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10490268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37686733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cenacchi V, Furlanis G, Menichelli A, Lunardelli A, Pesavento V, Manganotti P. Co-ultraPEALut in Subjective Cognitive Impairment Following SARS-CoV-2 Infection: An Exploratory Retrospective Study. Brain Sci. 2024. Mar 20;14(3):293.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10968982</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38539680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Versace V, Ortelli P, Dezi S, Ferrazzoli D, Alibardi A, Bonini I, et al. Co-ultramicronized palmitoylethanolamide/luteolin normalizes GABAB-ergic activity and cortical plasticity in long COVID-19 syndrome. Clin Neurophysiol. 2023. Jan;145:81&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9650483</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36455453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arumugham VB, Rayi A. Intravenous Immunoglobulin (IVIG). 2023 Jul 3. In: StatPearls [Internet]. Treasure Island (FL): StatPearls Publishing; 2024. Jan&#x2013;.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32119333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwab I, Nimmerjahn F. Intravenous immunoglobulin therapy: how does IgG modulate the immune system? Nat Rev Immunol. 2013. Mar;13(3):176&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23411799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai CC, Chen WC, Chen CY, Wei YF. The effect of intravenous immunoglobulins on the outcomes of patients with COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Expert Rev Anti Infect Ther. 2022. Oct;20(10):1333&#x2013;1340.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35786174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCarthy MW. Intravenous immunoglobulin as a potential treatment for long COVID. Expert Opin Biol Ther. 2023. Jul-Dec;23(12):1211&#x2013;1217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38100573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kotecha P, Light A, Checcucci E, Amparore D, Fiori C, Porpiglia F, et al. Repurposing of drugs for COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Panminerva Med. 2022. Mar;64(1):96&#x2013;114.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33073552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>